Hey, yo, yo,
嘿 哟 哟
pack the chrome sounds by like mrs.
把铬的声音包起来 就像夫人
Jones, liverpool mathematics.
琼斯 利物浦数学
We have the devil spoken stone.
我们有魔鬼说话的石头
Up one heads,
在我们开始搭讪的时候
the bed make shot some little when we get started for chat up,
床上弄了一些小镜头
everyone can down with us this beginning.
每个人都会和我们一起开始
I'll get two people in new york city easy, evan,
我在纽约很容易就能抓到两个人 埃文
and then brooklyn dva is the finest jail in seattle and they put the greek.
然后布鲁克林的dva是西雅图最好的监狱 他们把希腊人关起来了
These people that are helping us out and staying true to us.
这些人帮助我们走出困境 忠于我们
Since the beginning.
从一开始
I want to thank carnegie mellon for not firing me for another year.
我要感谢卡内基梅隆大学没有再解雇我一年
That's always important.
这总是很重要的
The core sponsor for this semester is going to be amazon.
这学期的核心赞助商将是亚马逊
Amazon is the largest database vendor in the world in terms of market cap,
就市值而言 亚马逊是世界上最大的数据库供应商
how much money they're making.
他们赚了多少钱
Right?
对的
They make all the money on the store,
他们在商店上赚了所有的钱
make a lot of money aws but they make a ton of money on databases.
在aws上赚了很多钱 但他们在数据库上赚了很多钱
Redshift aurora or the dynamo db they have a ton of stuff.
红移极光或发电机DB他们有一吨的东西
Usually oracle was number one.
通常甲骨文是第一名
Actually, maybe microsoft is number one for a while, too.
事实上 也许微软在一段时间内也是第一
Amazon is officially number one as of which microsoft might be number 100,
亚马逊（Amazon）是官方排名第一的公司 而微软（Microsoft）可能是排名第100的公司
whatever they're making a ton of money.
不管他们赚了多少钱
Anyway, they're helping us with the course logistics and sponsor goes.
不管怎样 他们正在帮助我们安排课程的后勤工作 赞助商也去了
We're really appreciative of that.
我们对此非常感激
And then the end of the semester,
然后到了学期末
somebody will come give from the redshift team come and give a tech talk
红移团队的人会来做一个关于他们正在建造的
about the system that they're building.
系统的技术演讲
We will discuss redshift throughout the semester.
我们将在整个学期中讨论红移
A lot of the techniques that will describe during the semester
很多技术将在学期中描述
they're actually implementing in their system.
他们实际上在他们的系统中实施
I quickly want to go over the course logistics and what the expected
我很快就想回顾一下课程的逻辑和本学期的预期
for the semester,
但我肯定
but I must have had most of the time on the history of databases,
花了大部分时间在数据库的历史上
because I find that part more interesting.
因为我觉得这部分更有趣
And then as I sent the email out over the weekend,
然后当我在周末发出电子邮件时
it would be based on the two readings.
它将基于两个读数
Again, it's not meant to be like deep into the internal of data systems.
同样 它并不意味着要深入到数据系统的内部
Just to give you perspective of what the landscape looks like,
只是为了让您了解前景是什么样子的
why we're spending all the time talking
为什么我们一直在讨论关系数据库
about relational databases and not other things.
而不是其他东西
So a lot of you guys are here for obvious reasons you want to take this course.
所以你们中的很多人来这里的原因很明显 你们想上这门课
But just as the final pitch,
但就像最后的演讲一样
i'll say the things that we talk about this semester for database systems
我要说的是我们这学期讨论的数据库系统
and particularly for analytical database systems,
特别是分析数据库系统
these are hard problems not ever can do it.
这些都是永远做不到的难题
And companies pay a lot of money for students,
公司为学生支付了很多钱
not coming to this class from other places as well that have experience
而不是从其他地方来上这门课
in working database systems.
因为他们有数据库系统的工作经验
If you're just a random javascript programmer,
如果你只是一个随机的JavaScript程序员
they're not going to be touching davis and turtles same way.
他们不会以同样的方式接触Davis和Turtles
They're not going to be touching the kernel in an operating system, right?
他们不会触及操作系统的内核 对吗
They don't want people off the street.
他们不想让人们离开这条街
They want people to understand fundamentally how these systems are working.
他们希望人们从根本上了解这些系统是如何工作的
These are the things that we're going to cover.
这些就是我们要讲的内容
This is not the full list,
这不是完整的名单
but these are just some of the former students that have worked with us
但这些只是一些以前和我们一起上这门课的学生
in taking this class and places that they've gone.
以及他们去过的地方
These are the ones I have photos a there's way more than i'm missing,
这些是我有照片的 比我错过的要多得多
but these are the ones that I I could quickly find.
但这些是我能很快找到的
Three of them are with me at my startup at autogen,
他们中的三个和我一起在我的创业公司AutoGen工作
some of the best ones as well.
其中一些也是最好的
All right.
好吧
So the unlike in previous years where you try to cover
所以不像前几年
maybe in memory database systems,
你可能会在内存中讨论数据库系统
and spend a little time discussing transaction systems,
并花一点时间讨论事务系统
this semester, we're only going to focus on analytical database systems,
这学期 我们将只关注分析型数据库系统
just because this is sort of what the hot thing is right now.
只是因为这是现在最热门的事情
And there's a lot of money sloshing around a lot of systems being built.
有大量的资金在许多正在建设的系统中流动
And to sort of understand we want to understand what the state of the art
为了理解 我们想要了解艺术的现状
is and how we got to the point where we are today.
以及我们是如何走到今天这一步的
The goal for you guys is that not only we become aware of what
你们的目标是
these systems actually are.
我们不仅要了解这些系统实际上是什么
What are the key features about them and help you to sort of understand
它们的关键特性是什么 它们可以帮助您了解一种
the trade offs between one system design or implementation versus
系统设计或实现与另一种系统设计或实现之间的
another?
权衡
You'll hopefully also become proficient in writing high quality systems code,
希望你也能熟练地编写高质量的系统代码
right?
对吗
Doing documentation and testing and doing code reviews.
做文档和测试 做代码审查
Right?
对的
These are soft skills that can be important when you go out in the real world,
这些都是软技能 当你在现实世界中进行新
new systems development,
系统开发时
that it's not something like there's any class to say,
这些技能可能很重要 这不像任何课程所说的
here's how to write documentation.
这是如何编写文档
Here's how to write test code.
下面是如何编写测试代码
It's just things you sort of have to pick up as you go along.
这只是你在前进的过程中必须学会的东西
The projects will be designed such that you'll get exposure to these sort
这些项目将被设计成这样
of best practices on how to do these to work on data systems.
你将接触到这些关于如何在数据系统上工作的最佳实践
This course, also, too, is only going to cover state of the art topics.
本课程也只会涵盖最先进的主题
I'm assuming everyone has taken a database class,
我假设每个人都上过数据库课程
either last semester or four forty five six, 45.
要么是上学期 要么是四四五六 45
What you're undergrad like,
你是个大学生
we're not going to go over to the basic of what a join is, right?
我们不会讨论什么是联合的基础知识 对吧
Talk,
说起来
we assume how to do a hash join.
我们假设如何进行哈希连接
We'll talk about how to do it parallel and do it, make it run fast.
我们将讨论如何并行地做 让它运行得更快
The topics that we're going to cover.
我们将要讨论的主题
First start off talking about storage models and compression.
首先 开始讨论存储模型和压缩
And actually, how do you represent data in files on disk?
实际上 如何表示磁盘上文件中的数据
Then we'll talk about how to do query execution using sort
然后
of modern techniques like vectorization and compilation.
我们将讨论如何使用向量化和编译等现代技术来执行查询
Then we'll talk about modern join algorithms.
然后 我们将讨论现代连接算法
Networking protocols are getting things out of the data in and out of the database.
网络协议将数据中的内容输入和输出数据库
Then we'll spend a little time talking about how to do query optimization,
然后 我们将花一点时间讨论如何进行查询优化
go much deeper than we were able to cover in the inter class.
这比我们在inter类中讨论的要深入得多
If you look at the schedule,
如果你看一下时间表
the last four or five lectures are actually targeting single database systems.
最后四到五节课实际上是针对单一数据库系统的
There's a whole lecture on snowflake, a whole lecture on data bricks,
有一个关于雪花的讲座
a whole lecture on big query of drama.
一个关于数据砖块的讲座 一个关于戏剧大查询的讲座
The idea is that we want to take all the things we discussed
我的想法是
throughout the semester,
我们想把我们整个学期讨论的所有事情
understand the basics of them,
了解它们的基础知识
and then look at a real system that implements all these things.
然后看看实现所有这些功能的真实系统
And try to understand like, why are they doing this a certain way?
试着去理解 他们为什么要以某种方式做这件事
Or what are the benefits?
或者有什么好处
Or what are the disadvantages of the approaches that they're taking?
或者他们所采取的方法的缺点是什么
Again, i'm assuming you've taken an intro davis class.
再说一次 我假设你上过戴维斯的入门课程
We're not going to cover sort of the basics of sql and other things.
我们不打算介绍SQL的基础知识和其他内容
So all the website is up to date.
所有的网站都是最新的
I I haven't updated the homepage because I try to get,
我还没有更新主页
I try to use dolly to have like the last supper and in the middle,
因为我试着 我试着用多莉来做最后的晚餐 在中间
it didn't work out very well.
效果不是很好
I've got to work on it anyway.
不管怎样 我得继续努力
So the website is up to date.
所以网站是最新的
So the syllabus and the schedule is all there.
所以教学大纲和时间表都在那里
For the most part, it's stable.
在大多数情况下 它是稳定的
So if you understand what's expected for you in the course,
所以 如果你明白这门课对你的期望
please go look at that.
请去看看
I'll say this throughout a couple of times in the beginning, right?
我会在开始的时候说几次 对吗
For academic honesty,
对于学术诚信
again, this is the advanced level class.
再次强调 这是高级水平课程
I assume everyone here is smart.
我想这里的每个人都很聪明
Therefore, you don't need to cheat.
因此 你不需要作弊
If you do cheat, we will take you over to warner hall and deal with that.
如果你作弊 我们会把你带到华纳大厅去处理
If you went in doubt,
如果你有疑问
if you're not sure about doing something like I have
如果你不确定是否要做一些事情
this little stupid code that somebody wrote in get hub,
比如我有一个人在Get Hub中编写的愚蠢的代码
can I use it in my project?
我可以在我的项目中使用它吗
If you're not sure,
如果你不确定
then just ask myself at the ta my office hours to be mondays and wednesdays,
那就在助教那里问问我自己 我的办公时间是周一和周三
the hour before class,
上课前的一小时
upstairs on the line floor.
在楼上的一层
And then we can talk about anything you want,
然后我们可以谈论任何你想要的东西
any of the projects and papers.
任何项目和论文
How to get a database job?
如何获取数据库作业
I have a bunch of database shirts.
我有一堆数据库衬衫
My office, the company send me.
我的办公室 公司派我来的
Please come and get some,
请来买一些
because i'm kind of getting a little hoarder level because they send
因为我有点囤积症
a bunch of me during the pandemic.
因为他们在流感大流行期间给我送来了一堆
I have a bunch of boxes.
我有一堆盒子
I've got to start getting rid of them.
我得开始摆脱他们了
So come and talk to me.
所以来和我谈谈
We have one ta when he's awesome.
我们有一个助教 当他很棒的时候
So he's my third year ph student.
他是我三年级的博士生
This is true.
这是真的
He is a former paralegal for like the sketchy law firm.
他以前是Sketchy律师事务所的律师助理
He is a certified chicken farmer.
他是一名持证养鸡户
He is the number of ranked phd student at carnegie mellon for data
他是卡内基梅隆大学排名第一的博士生
for databases to be very clear.
因为数据库的数据非常清晰
So, again, he'll help me with the projects.
所以 再说一次 他会帮我做项目
He'll be a part of the conversations as we go along the semester.
他将成为我们这学期谈话的一部分
So by all means, leverage him.
所以一定要利用他
If you have questions.
如果你有问题
The expectations are 33 things.
期望是33件事
There's reading assignments, projects, and the final exam.
有阅读作业 项目和期末考试
Every class will have one assigned reading,
除了今天的课
except for today's class.
每节课都会有一篇指定阅读
And they'll be indicated by the icon here.
它们将由此处的图标指示
I'll post on piazza what's actually expected in in these in these reading reviews.
我将在Piazza上发布这些阅读评论中真正期待的内容
But the main ideas ii want you to get out of is like, read the paper,
但我想让你们了解的主要想法是
understand what they're doing,
阅读论文 理解他们在做什么
understand all the things that we talked about,
理解我们讨论的所有事情
how to put, how would it fit together in a higher system,
如何把它放在一个更高的系统中
a higher level system.
一个更高层次的系统中
Then.
然后
I'm also curious.
我也很好奇
I don't understand what are the workloads that you to evaluate
我不明白您要评估
the the implementation for analytical databases.
分析数据库实施的工作负载是什么
It's most likely going to be tpch and tpcds over and over again.
最有可能的是一次又一次的TPCH和TPCD
It's good just to know what these things are,
知道这些东西是什么是很好的
so that when we go into project one, project two, actually, or project three,
这样当我们进入项目一
you'll have an idea of what workloads you can use based
项目二或项目三时
on the papers you've read.
你就会根据你读过的论文知道你可以使用哪些工作负载
And there's a google form here that is live,
这里有一个实时的谷歌表单
and then there will be a drop down.
然后会有一个下拉菜单
You fill that out.
你把它填好
Yes?
是的
It should be three.
应该是三个
You can skip three readings.
你可以跳过三次阅读
Sorry, i'll fix that.
对不起 我会解决的
Thank you.
谢谢
Again, all these reviews have to be your own writing.
再次 所有这些评论都必须是你自己写的
Some of these papers are pretty stated.
有些论文写得很好
They are like they came out last week,
他们就像上周出来的一样
and so they're probably not going to be a review on the internet.
所以他们可能不会在互联网上发表评论
You can use.
你可以用
You could try chat gpt see what happens.
你可以试试聊天GPT 看看会发生什么
Project one, we'll post next week.
项目一 我们将在下周发布
But you'd be basically writing a foreign data wrapper for post graphs,
但你基本上要为后图 过程
process, columnar data format, like a parquet file.
柱状数据格式编写一个外来数据包装器 就像一个镶木文件
The idea here is just to expose you to how to do vectors execution
这里的想法只是向您展示如何在post图的上下文
in the context of post graphs.
中执行向量
So we don't worry about do sql parsing.
所以我们不用担心做SQL解析
We don't worry about doing query planning.
我们不用担心进行查询计划
Let postcards handle all that.
让明信片来处理这一切
And the idea here would be that you'd be able to trade see the tradeoffs
这里的想法是 你可以在列上的
between your sort of custom engine on the column and our data
自定义引擎和我们的数据与后
versus post stresses,
压力之间进行权衡
row based iterator model.
基于行的迭代器模型
Again, what i'm saying, does it make sense?
再说一次 我说的有意义吗
Then that's not good because we cover these things in the interclass,
那就不好了 因为我们在课堂上讨论了这些东西
but make sure at least go back and look at them and understand what
但至少要确保回去看看它们
i'm talking about.
并理解我在说什么
Again, we'll post this next week.
同样 我们将在下周发布这篇文章
Project two is going to be writing an article for encyclopedia,
项目二将为百科全书写一篇文章
so we have an encyclopedia of databases.
所以我们有一个数据库百科全书
So every single database that i'm aware of the idea would be,
因此 我所知道的每一个数据库的想法都是
you go look at the documentation, go read,
你去看看文档 去阅读
maybe even run these systems,
甚至可能运行这些系统
go talk to the developers,
去与开发人员交谈
understand how they're implementing these different parts of the system
了解他们如何实现我们所关心的系统的这些
that we care about.
不同部分
And you'll be writing article for this.
你将为此写一篇文章
Ok?
好吧
Don't plagiarize with this,
不要抄袭
avoid marketing language.
避免使用营销语言
Sometimes I give the company's access to the website,
有时我让公司访问网站
and they'll say, like my database is the fastest whatever, right?
他们会说 我的数据库是最快的 对吗
And we have to remove all that.
我们必须把这些都去掉
Only say things that you can back up by specific claims.
只说那些你可以用具体的声明来支持的事情
Right?
对的
We more care about the internal and not like how people feel
我们更关心内部 而不是人们对数据库的感觉
about the database if that makes sense.
如果这是有意义的话
Project three will be a group project.
项目三将是小组项目
And the idea here would be some larger topic that you're interested in.
这里的想法是一些你感兴趣的更大的主题
That's based on the things we're discussing throughout the semester.
这是基于我们整个学期所讨论的事情
It doesn't have to be in postgres, but if you want,
它不一定要在postgres 但如果你想
it can be.
它可以
The idea here is that you just want to build something that exhibits
这里的想法是
some understanding of mastery of the materials we discussed
你只是想建立一些东西
throughout those masters.
展示对我们在这些大师中讨论的材料的掌握的一些理解
Again, i'll post some topics as we get closer.
再一次 当我们接近的时候 我会发布一些主题
You want to decide later until march.
你想晚些时候决定 直到三月
What do you exactly want to do?
你到底想做什么
I have some ideas of things that I want to do.
我对我想做的事情有一些想法
That could potentially turn into a short paper,
这可能会变成一篇简短的论文
or like a capturing project.
或者像一个捕捉项目
Again, we can discuss these as we go along.
同样 我们可以边走边讨论
Again, don't plagiarize.
再说一次 不要抄袭
And all your code has to be your code you submit to us has to be
你所有的代码都必须是你提交给我们的代码 必须是你的
yours unless you discuss and attributed same thing for the encyclopedia.
除非你在百科全书中讨论并引用了同样的东西
Please don't just copy from the from random things on internet.
请不要只是从互联网上随机复制的东西
1 year somebody copied from wiki pda and they had like a little
一年前 有人从维基掌上电脑复制
like there's the text and then the square bracket and then the number
他们有一些类似的文字 然后是方括号
for the citation.
然后是引用的数字
So we had to go deal with that again.
所以我们不得不再次处理这件事
So the reason why i'm keep showing this because this is on video now.
所以我一直在展示这个的原因是因为这个现在在视频上
Because then if you guys do plagiarize,
因为如果你们真的剽窃了
and then I go to turn you in.
我就去告发你们
I show them the video link on youtube, or like, here's me discussing this.
我给他们看YouTube上的视频链接 或者说 我在这里讨论这个
And you're screwed.
你完蛋了
There'll be a final exam, but it'll be take home.
将会有一次期末考试 但它会被带回家
Long form questions.
长格式问题
I did try chat gbt and it was not able to answer them.
我试着和GBT聊天 但它无法回答他们
So who knows whether how much better that will get?
所以谁知道会有多好呢
So it's either that like,
所以要么是喜欢
I wonder if it's a limitation of chat gbt or whether my questions are just terrible.
我想知道这是否是聊天GBT的限制 或者我的问题是否很糟糕
And it can't parse them acting with you is like really bad at like kind
它不能解析它们 和你一起表演真的很糟糕
of like specialized questions like you can answer
就像你可以很好地回答基本的计算机科学问题
basic computer science questions really well,
但一旦你和专家打交道
but once you dealt with the specialist you kind of like drops the ball
你就会掉链子 但很糟糕
but like terribly but it phrases an amber.
但它说的是琥珀
So you think it's right,
所以你认为这是正确的
it's like multi version current control is important because it
就像多版本当前控制很重要
does multiversioning like thanks.
因为它像Thanks一样进行多版本控制
That's what it told me.
这就是它告诉我的
Right?
对的
Grey breakdown is like this.
灰色分解是这样的
Again, this is on the syllabus,
同样 这是在教学大纲上
no big surprises here.
这里没有太大的惊喜
And then the chorus mailing list, everything will be on piazza.
然后是合唱团的邮件列表 所有的东西都会在广场上
If you have any technical questions as about project
如果你有任何关于项目一和潜在项目三的技术问题
one and potentially project three,
在我们进行的
as we go along.
过程中
Please post on piazza.
请在广场上发帖
Don't email one of myself directly.
不要直接给自己发电子邮件
And if anything else like your health issues,
如果你有任何健康问题
whatever you have going on,
无论你有什么问题
please email directly.
请直接发电子邮件
Any questions about this?
对此有什么问题吗
Let's get to this databases.
让我们来看看这个数据库
Yeah.
是啊
1 year somebody complained on youtube.
一年前有人在YouTube上抱怨
I you spent 25 minutes discussing logistics of the course,
如果你花了25分钟讨论课程的后勤工作
get to the good stuff.
那就是好东西
So here we are.
所以我们在这里
As I said,
正如我所说
this is sort of my bridge history of the last 50,
这是我过去50
60 years of databases.
60年数据库的桥梁历史
So we're not going to go too deep into any one topic,
因此 我们不会深入讨论任何一个主题
but it's a going to an overview of the lay of the land that like,
但我们将对这一领域进行概述
I think what's actually really interesting about this is that databases are
我认为真正有趣的是
a hot area right now in both research and in in industry.
数据库目前在研究和行业中都是一个热门领域
And yet they're 60 years old.
但他们已经60岁了
First one is going to be from the 1960s.
第一个是20世纪60年代的
Right?
对的
It just shows you how important they are and how hard the problem is.
它只是告诉你它们有多重要 问题有多难
If like,
如果喜欢
it's clearly not a solved problem.
这显然不是一个解决的问题
It's gonna this lecture sort of derived from two papers.
这节课是从两篇论文中衍生出来的
The first one was called what goes around comes around and is written
第一本书名为《What Goes Around Comes Around》
by mike stern bakker and joe hellers stein in 2006.
由迈克·斯特恩·巴克（Mike Stern Bakker）和乔·海勒斯·斯坦（Joe Heller Stein）于2006年撰写
And it's basically mikes assessment of the database industry and how he
这基本上是迈克对数据库行业的评价
was right for the last 40 years.
以及他在过去40年里是如何正确的
Mike won the touring award in 2014,
迈克在2014年赢得了巡回演出奖
so I would agree with him.
所以我同意他的观点
Then the paper, this other one draft I sent you.
然后是论文 我寄给你的另一份草稿
This is mike.
这是迈克
And I wrote this last year where we basically looked at where this paper
我去年写了这篇文章 我们基本上是从这篇论文停止的地方开始的
left off and said what's the next sixteen seventeen years
然后说接下来的16年和17年是什么
And this was actually triggered by me,
这实际上是由我引发的
because there was some like postman hacker news or somebody's like,
因为有一些像邮差黑客新闻之类的人
I don't know why people keep using relational databases.
我不知道为什么人们一直在使用关系数据库
Graph database is the way to go.
图形数据库是一条可行之路
And I was like, all right,
我想 好吧
I said that the mic, let's write the new ones.
我说麦克风 让我们写新的
The major take away.
主要带走
What you guys get from this is that again,
你们从这里得到的是
even though databases are really old,
即使数据库真的很老
the concept is really old.
这个概念也很老
They are highly relevant today,
它们在今天是高度相关的
because the other day, every application,
因为前几天 每个应用程序
what are they essentially doing?
它们本质上在做什么
Right?
对的
They're exposing some user interface for for either a human
它们为人类或另一台机器或与数据库
or another machine or something to interact with a database.
交互的东西公开了一些用户界面
Right?
对的
What's going to be interesting is a lot of the things that will cover this semester.
有趣的是这学期要讲的很多东西
These are not new ideas.
这些都不是新的想法
They're not new concepts.
它们不是新概念
I'm going to see, I said this in andrew class.
我要去看看 我在安德鲁的课上说过
I'll keep saying this over and over again throughout the semester.
我会在整个学期里一遍又一遍地说这句话
Ibm did a lot of this stuff in the 1970s.
IBM在20世纪70年代做了很多这样的事情
Just obviously, the harbor was much different.
很明显 港口很不一样
The landscape was much different,
前景是非常不同的
but a lot of the things we'll talk about will be just modern incarnations
但我们将谈论的许多东西将只是ibm
of what ibm invented.
发明的现代化身
The years ago,
几年前
we're going to spend a whole lecture on query compilation,
我们将花一整堂课的时间来讲解查询编译
how to take a segal query,
如何将Segal查询转换为查询计划
turn into a query plan and then converted that query plan into machine code.
然后将该查询计划转换为机器码
Ibm did that in the 1970s.
IBM在20世纪70年代就这样做了
It was system r they did it in an assembly.
这是系统R 他们在一个组件中做的
Now we use lbm but again, the techniques are not new.
现在我们使用LBM 但同样 这些技术并不是新的
The other big thing is going to happen and you'll see this the rest
另一件大事将会发生 在你的余生中
of your life is that every 10 years somebody's gonna come along and say,
你会看到每隔10年
hey, sequel is stupid.
就会有人走过来说 嘿 续集是愚蠢的
Relational model that's slow, right?
关系模型很慢 对吧
We can do it better.
我们可以做得更好
Here's my new data system that doesn't use, at least the model is equal.
这是我的新数据系统 不使用 至少模型是平等的
Right?
对的
Everyone's gonna go excited like this is the future sql
每个人都会很兴奋 就像未来的sql
是旧的
is old,
sequel is busted, we don't want to use that.
续集是失败的 我们不想用它
And then low and behold people realize the relational model was
然后看吧 人们意识到关系模型是一个好主意
a good idea or sql
或者sql
是一个好主意
is a good idea.
Either that thing that the new invention that comes along,
要么是新发明出现
either that fails,
要么是失败
or the whatever ideas that this new idea,
或者这个新的想法
this new concept or new data system has letters get adopted
这个新的概念或者新的数据系统有字母的任何想法被采纳
by the sequel standard and by the racial model.
按照续集的标准和种族模式
Then that thing goes away.
然后那东西就消失了
All right?
好吧
So I think i've seen this in my own life,
所以我想我在自己的生活中已经看到了这一点
like no sequel is a hot thing.
就像没有续集是一件热门的事情
People said sequel slow, sequel, stupid,
人们说sql慢 sql愚蠢
relation models too, but you want to do documents,
关系型模型也是
you need jason and everybody built all these jason databases.
但你想做文档 你需要json和每个人都建立了所有这些json
数据库
Right?
对的
And then now we're at the point where maybe that's a bad idea for everything.
然后现在我们到了也许这对一切都是个坏主意的地步
Json is good for some things.
json对某些事情很在行
The relation model now supports json.
关系型模型现在支持json
And then all the no sql systems that said sql is a bad idea.
然后所有没有续集的系统都说sql是个坏主意
Every one of them except for redis supports sql,
除了redis 他们每个人都支持sql
right?
对吧
Mongo support to see last year.
去年mongo支持看
Right?
对的
So you're going to see this throughout the theme,
所以你会在整个主题中看到这一点
as we go along is that at least once we get past and once the racial model
至少一旦我们过去了
gets invented,
一旦种族模式被发明出来
people will say every 10 years it's stupid.
人们每10年就会说这是愚蠢的
And then it turns out it was mark my board and you'll see this the rest
结果发现是马克在我的冲浪板上
of your life.
你的余生都会看到这个
I guarantee you,
我向你保证
let's start at the very beginning,
让我们从头开始
1960s.
1960年代
So to the best of my knowledge,
所以据我所知
at least what is considered conventional wisdom,
至少被认为是传统智慧
the very first database system,
第一个数据库系统
our sort of general purpose database system,
我们的通用数据库系统
was this thing called integrated data store or iids and I say general purpose,
被称为集成数据存储或iids 我说的通用
what I mean is that it was a database system that was designed to support
我的意思是它是一个数据库系统
arbitrary data sets or databases.
旨在支持任意数据集或数据库
Right?
对的
Obviously,
显然
you can write a little python application yourself and read and write files.
您可以自己编写一个小型Python应用程序并读写文件
That's just for exactly that one database.
这只是一个数据库
That's not what I mean by this, like those things sort of existed.
这不是我的意思 就像那些东西存在一样
But this was specifically to say we could then reuse the system
但这特别是说
for another application or another customer.
我们可以将该系统重新用于另一个应用程序或另一个客户
Ge got this for.
通用电气得到了这个
It was like some timber company out of seattle that had
这就像西雅图的一些木材公司有一个巨大的库存跟踪问题
a huge inventory tracking problem that they need to deal with.
他们需要处理
And said they built this thing called ids to handle that.
并说他们建立了一个叫做IDS的东西来处理这个问题
They end up spinning it out of that custom solution for the timber company
他们最终将其从木材公司的定制解决方案中分离出来
and try to sell it a as a standalone product.
并试图将其作为独立产品销售
Right?
对的
Like ge was trying to be a software vendor.
就像通用电气试图成为一家软件供应商一样
Is ge the hot thing in computers right now?
GE现在是计算机领域的热门产品吗
No.
不
Right.
对的
So what the huge mistake they did is that they had this company policy
所以他们犯了一个巨大的错误
at the time where ge said,
他们当时的公司政策是
if we're not number one in some industry,
如果我们在某个行业不是第一
we don't want to be in it at all.
我们就根本不想进入这个行业
So they were like the number three computer seller that wasn't good
所以他们就像是排名第三的电脑销售商
enough for them.
对他们来说不够好
And so they sold off their computing division to honeywell.
所以他们把计算机部门卖给了honeywell
Right?
对的
Then honeywell owned own owned ids and then they were sort of selling it
然后霍尼韦尔拥有自己的ID
for a while.
然后他们卖了一段时间
So there could be two key things about ids that are going to be bad ideas
因此 关于ids可能有两个关键的东西 这两个东西将是坏主意
that are going to then get fixed in their relation to model.
然后将在它们与模型的关系中得到修复
The first is to meet this network data model,
第一个是满足这个网络数据模型
and i'll explain what that is in a second.
第二个我会解释它是什么
And then the other one's going to be this notion of the tuple at a time query,
然后另一个是tuple-at-a-time query的概念
meaning like i'm going to write,
意思是我要写的
basically for loops in my program,
基本上是我的程序中的循环
iterate over one tuple at a time and do something.
一次迭代一个元组 然后做一些事情
But as we know, in sql, though,
但正如我们所知道的
we're an operator or bags or sets,
结果是 我们是一个运营商或包或设置
we declare what the thing we actually want to do.
我们宣布我们真正想做的事情
That then could apply to multiple tuples.
这可能适用于多个tuples
And that's me way more efficient.
这是我更有效率的方式
So ids didn't really take off as far as I know.
所以据我所知 身份证并没有真正流行起来
But what actually came out of the project was this thing called codacil.
但实际上这个项目产生的是一个叫做Codacil的东西
I I should do a survey before the class starts.
我应该在上课前做个调查
Who's ever heard of coda still?
谁还听说过尾波
Well, who not from the previous class?
好吧 谁不是上一届的
One of you code is always going to be the hot thing of databases.
你们中的一个代码总是会成为数据库中的热门话题
This was the thing that everyone's going to build for their database.
这是每个人都要为他们的数据库建立的东西
And obviously, we don't.
很明显 我们没有
So there was this guy, charles bachman,
所以有一个人
who worked in ids and he saw,
查尔斯·巴赫曼 他在ids工作 他看到了
she saw the need for having a standard way for cobalt programmers
她看到了cobalt程序员需要一种标准的方式来
to interact with the database system.
与数据库系统交互
They proposed this data model and this query api called codes film
他们提出了这个数据模型和这个名为codes film的查询api
that incorporated the network data model from and the tube
它结合了ids上一张幻灯片中的网络数据模型
out of time query model from the previous slide from ids and they said
和tube out of time查询模型
this is
他们说这将成为
going to be the standard going forward.
未来的标准
So then bachmann left ids and he worked at this thing called que lane,
然后巴赫曼离开了ids 他在一个叫que lane的地方工作
which has been bought and sold over many years.
这个地方已经被买卖了很多年
And he helped build a new version of a network data model based
他帮助建立了一个基于代码单元的网络数据模型的新版本 称为idms
on code cell called idms and this thing is actually still around today.
这个东西实际上今天仍然存在
You're obviously, if you're a brand new startup, you wouldn't use this,
很明显 如果你是一家全新的创业公司
right?
你不会用这个 对吧
This is for like legacy applications.
这适用于类似的遗留应用程序
So the networking model is going to look like this.
所以网络模型看起来是这样的
So say I have this example where i'm say i'm nasa.
我举个例子 我说我是NASA
This is actually a real example.
这其实是一个真实的例子
I'm nasa and i'm building a rocket for the go to the moon
我是美国国家航空航天局
by the apollo moon mission.
我正在为阿波罗登月计划建造一枚火箭
A it's a huge engineering project.
A这是一个庞大的工程项目
I need to keep track of all the parts that are going to my rocket
我需要跟踪我的火箭的所有部件
and what manufacturer or what company can provide them for me.
以及什么制造商或什么公司可以为我提供这些部件
Right?
对的
So they would have this database where you have suppliers and the parts.
所以他们会有这个数据库 你有供应商和零件
Then you keep track of what supplier can provide certain parts
然后你跟踪什么供应商可以提供某些零件
and what price and what size and so forth.
什么价格 什么尺寸等等
Under the network data model,
在网络数据模型下
you would have the high level entities like you would have a supplier,
您将拥有高级实体
the name of the company that could provide the part or provide parts.
就像您将拥有供应商一样 即可以提供零件或提供零件的公司的名称
You have the part that you need.
你有你需要的部分
And then you have this other set that says,
然后你有另一套
here's the for this supplier,
这是这个供应商的
they will supply this part, this price.
他们将提供这个零件 这个价格
So you could have these high level entities.
所以你可以拥有这些高级实体
But then you would have to implicitly have these sets.
但是你必须隐式地拥有这些集合
Here what i'm showing in italics, right?
这是我用斜体显示的 对吗
You would have the supplies and the supplied by,
你会有供应品和供应者
you would say I have a supplier and there will be a supply
你会说我有一个供应商
that's in the set of supplies.
在供应品集合中会有一个供应品
Now if I want to find find me all the parts that a supplier supplies,
现在 如果我想找到供应商提供的所有零件
I would have to do a bunch of nest of four lips.
我必须做一堆四个嘴唇的巢穴
Go look over every supplier here,
去看看这里的每一个供应商
look over all their supply sets,
看看他们所有的供应集
get the supply types, and then reverse go back up there, right?
得到供应类型 然后反过来回到那里 对吗
You basically write a bunch of these nets of four lips,
你基本上写了一堆四个嘴唇的网
and you're doing this over one tube at a time.
你一次在一个管子上做这个
Another problem is going to be is that actually,
另一个问题是 实际上
the way you sort of look like this,
你看起来像这样
if you actually have an instance of this,
如果你真的有一个这样的例子
right?
对吧
You have supplier supplies of parts,
你有供应商供应的零件
and then you would have these auxiliary tables
然后你会有这些
and basically cross reference tables you would have,
辅助表和基本的交叉引用表
or you keep pointers to the actual objects.
或者你保留指向实际对象的指针
And so these red lines i'm drawing here.
所以我在这里画了这些红线
These are actually pointers like physical pointers to like,
这些实际上是类似物理指针的指针
here's the location of this record on disk or in memory.
这是该记录在磁盘或内存中的位置
Right?
对的
Again.
又
So now, when you get your looping through,
所以现在 当你通过循环时
try to find all the suppliers apply a certain part.
试着找到所有的供应商来申请某一部分
You'd have to look at the first one,
您必须查看第一个
and then you do a look up to find the record in this entity.
然后查找该实体中的记录
And i'm going to call it a table because it's not.
我要称它为桌子 因为它不是
And then you would follow the pointer to jump here.
然后你会跟着指针跳到这里
And then potentially,
然后潜在地
you could have a pointer to go back in the other direction.
你可以有一个指针回到另一个方向
Right?
对的
So the queries are very complex, right?
所以查询非常复杂 对吧
This is all written in cobalt.
这都是用钴写的
And it was less efficient because again,
它的效率较低
you're operating over a single tuple at a time.
因为你一次只在一个tuple上操作
It was easily corruptible.
它很容易被打断
So if this thing gets if this the harbor is crappy back,
所以如果这个东西得到了
then this supplies or supplied by these collections of data,
如果这个港口是蹩脚的 那么这个提供或由这些数据的集合提供
these pointers.
这些指针
If this thing gets corrupted,
如果这个东西被破坏了
your whole database is host,
你的整个数据库都是主机
because now you have no way to to traverse and find things,
因为现在你没有办法遍历和查找东西
understand the relationships between these objects.
了解这些对象之间的关系
All right.
好吧
So the next big system that was in the 1960s was this thing called ims
所以在20世纪60年代的下一个大系统是这个叫做IMS的东西
and this actually was built for the apollo moon mission.
它实际上是为阿波罗登月任务建造的
Ibm was responsible for the building out of database to keep track
IBM负责构建数据库
of all the parts they were.
以跟踪它们的所有部分
Nasa was buying to build the rockets.
美国国家航空航天局购买建造火箭
And again,
同样
just like for ge and is they built a sort of custom database system
就像ge和is一样 他们为该项目建立了一种自定义数据库系统
for the project and then realized it was useful for other customers,
然后意识到它对其他客户有用
and they spun it out as a separate product.
他们将其作为一个单独的产品
This thing still exists today.
这件事今天仍然存在
And ibm makes a ton of money on these things.
IBM在这些东西上赚了很多钱
And this data has been till today.
这个数据一直到今天
If you ever used an atm machine or anything in the bank,
如果你曾经使用过ATM机或银行里的任何东西
a lot of them are still using ims as they set up in the 70s.
他们中的很多人仍然在使用70年代建立的IMS
If it's not broken,
如果它没坏
don't fix it.
就不要修理它
Ims is going to use what's called a hierarchical data model.
IMS将使用所谓的分层数据模型
And just like the network data model is going to use a tube out of time queries.
就像网络数据模型一样 将使用管超时查询
Then another big thing is that it's going to support a programmer to find
另一件重要的事情是它将支持程序员找到
physical data structures,
物理数据结构
meaning like if I have a collection of data like a table,
意思是如果我有一个像表一样的数据集合
I don't use your table because they wouldn't call it that,
我不会使用你的表 因为他们不会这样称呼它
but assume it's a table.
而是假设它是一个表
I would actually tell the database system.
我会告诉数据库系统
I want to store it as a hash table,
我想把它存储为哈希表
or I want to store it as ab plus tree.
或者我想把它存储为AB加树
Then based on what I told it,
然后根据我告诉它的
I wanted to store it as you then got a different api that allowed you
我想存储它 然后你得到一个不同的api
traversing the data,
允许你遍历数
because you can't do range queries and hash tables,
据因为你不能做范围查询和哈希表
but you can't do it on b plus trees.
但你不能在b加树上做
Go back to our example here.
回到我们的例子
We have a supplier now.
我们现在有供应商了
I'm an idiot because this i'm leaving plug of a clicker in.
我是个白痴 因为我把遥控器的插头留在里面了
That's pathetic.
太可悲了
Right?
对的
So I have a supplier.
所以我有一个供应商
And now they have parts that looks a little bit better, right?
现在他们有了看起来更好的部分 对吧
Because now I don't have to have all this extra stuff.
因为现在我不需要这些多余的东西了
Now,
现在
but I do have an implicit relationship between explicit relation
但我确实在供应商和零件之间的显式关系之间
between the supplier and the part.
有一个隐式关系
A part can only supply by one particular supplier.
一个零件只能由一个特定的供应商供应
Right now, if I go to my instance,
现在 如果我去我的实例
right?
是吧
Say this first vendor,
比如说第一个供应商
they supply batteries.
他们供应电池
I would have to have another whole record for that.
我必须有另一个完整的记录
And then I would have to have another record for the second vendor
然后我必须为第二个供应商提供另一张唱片
who's playing maybe the same batteries,
他们可能使用相同的电池
but a different price.
但价格不同
So let's say now if I change the name of the of the part from batteries to
现在 假设我将部件的名称从batteries更改为on a
on a brand name battery,
brand name battery
whatever I want to change this field here,
无论我想在这里更改什么
i've got to go through and change every single record instance
我都必须检查并更改
of where the batteries exist.
电池所在位置的每个记录实例
Because you were basically repeating information because you couldn't have
因为你基本上是在重复信息
one part be supplied by multiple suppliers in this model.
因为在这个模型中 你不能让一个零件由多个供应商提供
The other problem you're going to have, also, too, is,
你还会遇到的另一个问题是
as I said about the,
正如我所说的
since the system exposes the the ability to tell how you
由于系统公开了你实际上想要如何存储数据的能力
actually want to store data,
一个哈希表与B集群或其他什么
a hash table versus b cluster or whatever,
那么如果我改变主意
then if I changed my mind and I said I sorted the hash table,
我说我对哈希表进行了排序
but I want to do range queries.
但我想做范围查询
Let me switch it to ab plus tree.
让我把它切换到AB加树
You had no way of easily changing that.
你没有办法轻易改变这一点
You had to actually dump the data out,
实际上 您必须将数据转储出来
then load it back under the new data structure.
然后将其加载回新的数据结构中
Then you actually have to go update your application code,
然后你实际上必须去更新你的应用程序代码
because now it expose the hash the b plus gapi instead of the hash table
因为现在它暴露了b+gapi的哈希
api there's no independence between the physical layer
而不是哈希表api 物理层和逻辑层之间没有独立性
and the logical layer what the data actually was.
数据实际上是什么
All this is sort of the, yes,
所有这些都是一种 是的
the system didn't support it with ims now in like twenty, 2003.
在2003年的20年里 系统不支持IMS
I I ai think they have asql veneer on top of it.
我人工智能认为他们在它上面有ASQL单板
Right?
对的
And ii think it still is a hard come on an e there was attempts to convert
我认为这仍然是一个很难的事情
it to racial model in the 80s rented pin out.
在80年代 有人试图把它转换成种族模式
But I this is like 1960s.
但我这就像20世纪60年代
This is the way.
这就是方法
So this is the motivation for the relational model.
这就是关系模型的动机
In the late 1960s,
在20世纪60年代末 有一个叫泰德·科德的家伙
there's this guy ted cod, who just finished his phd in math.
他刚刚完成了数学博士学位
He was working in ibm research,
他当时在ibm研究院工作
and he saw all of these ims programmers spending a lot of time rewriting
他看到所有这些ims程序员花费大量时间一遍又一遍地
for application code over and over again,
重写应用程序代码
because of this tight coupling between,
原因是物理层和逻辑层
again, the physical layer and the logical layer.
之间的这种紧密耦合
And so then he realized that,
然后他意识到
which is actually quite prescient that this is not scalable.
这实际上是相当有先见之明的 这是不可扩展的
Humans at some point, it could be way more expensive than computers.
在某种程度上 它可能比计算机更昂贵
At the time computers are super expensive, humans are cheap.
在计算机超级昂贵的时候 人类是廉价的
The opposite now, right?
现在正好相反 对吧
I can get an amazon instance,
我可以得到一个
a fraction of a penny an hour,
amazon实例
but a program is going to cost me 200 k how happens?
每小时只需一分钱 但一个程序将花费我20万美元 这是怎么回事
Just continue lecture,
继续讲课
not that one.
不是那个
What?
什么
Now i'm curious,
现在我很好奇
I don't know.
我不知道
Are you laughing at the 200 k for database programmer?
你在嘲笑数据库程序员的200K吗
That's a bit low?
那有点低
Anyway, data programs aren't cheap,
无论如何 数据程序并不便宜
but at the time it was slept,
但在它睡觉的时候
he saw all these people wasting their time over again,
他看到所有这些人又在浪费时间
rewriting the application.
重写应用程序
They saw the inefficiency of having this sort of two po at a time
他们看到了这种一次两个Po的编程API的低效率
programming api the relational model has sort of three key parts to it,
关系模型有三个关键部分
that again,
再一次
it serves as the background for all the racial modern racial data systems today.
它成为了今天所有现代种族数据系统的背景
The first of that,
首先 我们
we're going to store the database in simple data structures
将把数据库存储在简单的数据结构中
instead of this graph in the coder cell network model,
而不是编码器单元网络模型中的这个图
or this hierarchy under ims we're going to store tables relations.
或者ims下的这个层次结构 我们将存储表关系
So these single heap things.
所以这些单堆的东西
And if they have relations or if there are references to other tables,
如果它们有关系 或者有对其他表的引用
we just store that as again as another attribute in their relations.
我们只需将其作为另一个属性再次存储在它们的关系中
Right?
对的
No need to have explicit pointers to anything.
不需要任何明确的指针
The program is the way we're going to access the database
该程序是我们通过高级语言访问
through a high level language.
数据库的方式
Instead of writing these nested for loops,
而不是编写这些嵌套的for循环
they'll be able to say he didn't vent sequel at the time,
他们将能够说他当时没有发泄Sequel
but I sorry,
但很抱歉
there was not a programming language like siegel at the time,
当时没有像Siegel这样的编程语言
but he had this idea like, ok,
但他有这样的想法
there's a way to abstract what the actual physical materialization
好吧
of the physical structure of the database system.
有一种方法可以抽象数据库系统的物理结构的实际物理物化
And to say this is the answer I want.
这就是我想要的答案
And then a data system could figure it out for you.
然后数据系统会帮你算出来
Right?
对的
And then this also now means that because I have this abstraction
这也意味着
between the physical layer and the logical layer,
由于我在物理层和逻辑层之间进行了这种抽象
the the strategy just stored the data physically on disk or in memory,
该策略只是将数据物理地存储在磁盘或内存中
we left entirely up to the implementation.
我们完全由实现决定
Because based on what the queries wanted to do,
因为根据查询想要做的事情
it could decide here's the best way to store your data.
它可以决定存储数据的最佳方式
Right?
对的
The first paper on the racial model came out in 1969.
第一篇关于种族模式的论文发表于1969年
This is the very first one.
这是第一个
This is usually the one everyone cites as the
这通常是每个人都引用的一篇事实上的关系模型论文
as the de facto relational model paper that this came out in the cacm
该论文于1970年发表
in 1970.
在cacm上
But this was the very first one.
但这是第一个
We go back to our example before suppliers and supplies and parts.
我们回到供应商 供应品和零件之前的例子
Right?
对的
It looks like this.
它看起来像这样
It's essentially what the network model was,
它本质上是网络模型
but now I don't have these explicit membership sets.
但现在我没有这些明确的成员集
Then now if I want to sort of in a table or in tables in a relational database,
现在 如果我想在一个表或关系数据库中的
right now,
表中排序 现在
I have these foreign key references that are just attributes in the object.
我有这些外键引用 它们只是对象中的属性
And the data system can understand that this supplier number corresponds
数据系统可以理解这个供应商编号对应于另一个表
to some supplier number in this other table here.
中的某个供应商编号
We'll get to c equal to second,
我们会得到C等于2
but this was a radical idea.
但这是一个激进的想法
A sequel is a radical idea.
续集是一个激进的想法
Now we take it for granted because it's so prevalent,
现在我们认为它是理所当然的
but back then the criticism of the relational model was there's no way
因为它是如此普遍 但当时对关系模型的批评是没有办法数据库
a database of no way a piece of software.
没有办法软件
It's going to write queries as efficient as what a human can write.
它将编写与人类所能编写的查询一样高效的查询
This seems sort of strange,
这似乎有点奇怪
but it's sort of the same argument that people made back in the day,
但这与当年人们提出的论点相同
that there's no way a compiler could generate program code that is
即编译器不可能生成比人类编写的代码
more efficient than what a human could write.
更高效的程序代码
Sure that's potentially true for like highly skilled and embedded systems programmers.
当然 对于高技能的嵌入式系统程序员来说 这可能是真的
But nobody writes assembly today.
但是今天没有人写汇编
Right?
对的
Everybody writes in higher level languages and even higher like up in python.
每个人都用更高级的语言写作 甚至更高级的语言 比如Python
Right?
对的
But back then, again, this is like the sea compiler came out in 1970.
但在当时 这就像是1970年推出的SEA编译器
This was an insane idea and turned out it was correct.
这是一个疯狂的想法 事实证明它是正确的
The depends on the implementation of the query optimizer, how good it is.
这取决于查询优化器的实现 以及它有多好
And we'll see some papers that show how things go wrong.
我们会看到一些论文 说明事情是如何出错的
And that's certainly a hard problem.
这当然是个难题
But in general,
但一般来说
like a database system is going to generate a more efficient query plan
就像数据库系统将生成比一般程序员实际编写的更
than an average programmer could actually write.
有效的查询计划一样
And also,
而且
now it exposes the data system to people that are maybe art programmers,
现在它将数据系统暴露给可能是艺术程序员的人
like business analysts or people doing accounting reporting, right?
比如业务分析师或做会计报告的人 对吧
But they are not hardcore programmers.
但他们不是铁杆程序员
They can write sql, but maybe not can't write any cc plus.
他们可以编写SQL 但可能不能编写任何CC Plus
So ted cod put out the paper in 1970.
所以特德·科德在1970年发表了这篇论文
He was a mathematician,
他是个数学家
this paper here, it's actually not the hard to read.
这里的这篇论文 实际上并不难读
But when you read the criticisms of it or people talk about it at the time
但当你读到对它的批评 或者人们谈论它的时候
contemporary conversations about it,
当代关于它的谈话
people say it was inscrutable.
人们说它是高深莫测的
It was told was heavy on math,
据说它的数学很重
not.
不
But again, maybe 1970s, I don't know, maybe it was.
但是 也许是20世纪70年代 我不知道 也许是
He didn't propose a programming language in that paper.
他在那篇论文中并没有提出一种编程语言
He later did in 1974, 75,
他后来在1974年 75年
this thing called alpha didn't go anywhere.
这个叫做阿尔法的东西没有去任何地方
But it was all math at the time.
但当时都是数学
And he didn't actually build a system to prove that his idea was working
他实际上并没有建立一个系统来证明他的想法是可行的
could work.
What happened was there was a bunch of people saw his paper,
事情是这样的 有一群人看到了他的论文
said, hey,
说
I think this is a good idea and actually started building
嘿 我认为这是一个好主意
experimental systems to test that out.
并开始建立实验系统来测试它
The very first system that i'm aware of that did was this thing called
据我所知
the peter lee relational test vehicle,
第一个这样做的系统是一个叫做彼得·李关系测试工具的东西
which sounds like a 1970s, like druggie ban.
听起来像20世纪70年代的毒品禁令
But these are like people in the uk that basically read his paper, like,
但这些人就像英国人一样 基本上都读过他的论文
I think it's a good idea.
就像 我认为这是一个好主意
And they built sort of early prototypes from four sequel.
他们建立了四个续集的早期原型
It they talk about,
他们谈到
it could store massive data sets of like 1,002 poles like that was mind
它可以存储大量的数据集 比如1002个极点
blowing for them back of them.
这对他们来说是令人兴奋的
That one usually people forget about.
人们通常会忘记这一点
That's far as I know, that's the very first one.
据我所知 这是第一个
But there's two other projects that came1 or 2 years after system are at
但是还有另外两个项目是在ibm的system和berkeley的ingress之后1
ibm and then ingress at berkeley.
或2年出现的
These are considered the very first to relational data systems that
这些被认为是第一个关系数据系统
like try to or try to build something based on ted cards work
试图建立一些基于Ted卡片的工作
and actually build a real system.
并真正建立一个真正的系统
I think mimer sequel came out at a sweden,
我认为《哑剧续集》是在瑞典推出的
maybe a 1 or 2 years later,
可能是1年或2年后
but this is an act on a project.
但这是一个项目的行为
This still exists today.
这在今天仍然存在
Oracle with larry ellison, we know about that.
甲骨文和拉里·埃里森 我们知道这件事
And we'll cover that throughout the semester.
我们将在整个学期中讨论这个问题
Basically,
基本上
the it's all happening in silicon valley.
这一切都发生在硅谷
Larry elsin basically copy what ibm did.
Larry Elsin基本上复制了IBM的做法
He would literally call them on the phone and ask about like,
他会给他们打电话
how does this work?
问他们 这是怎么回事
And they would tell them because they were researchers didn't know,
他们会告诉他们 因为他们是研究人员 不知道
and he went and copied it.
他去复制了它
And then ingress eventually got commercialized at the university
然后ingress最终在70年代末在大学里商业化了
in the late 70s,
因为人们
because people actually started really using it because they understood
实际上开始真正使用它
the the certificates of the racial model.
因为他们了解种族模型的证书
But again, 1970s, it was not clear that it could have been coda, still,
但同样 在20世纪70年代 不清楚它是否可能是尾波
it could have been a relational model.
但它可能是一个关系模型
Eventually in the 1980s, relational model, one,
最终在20世纪80年代 关系模型 一
two things happened, three things happened.
发生了两件事 三件事
First is that ibm never commercialized system are they could have been
首先 ibm从未将系统商业化
a dominant player in the and they do this marketplace,
他们本可以在这个市场上占据主导地位
but they drop the baldness because they were making so much money on ims like,
但他们放弃了秃头 因为他们在ims上赚了很多钱
why would you kill the golden goose with this other new data system that
当你在ims上赚了这么多钱的时候
may not work when you're making so much money on ims but eventually they
你为什么要用另一个可能不起作用的新数据系统来杀死这只下金蛋的鹅呢
saw the light and they put out their
但最终他们看到了曙光
first relational database system called segal ds in 1981,
并在1981年推出了他们的第一个关系数据库系统
this had remnants of system r but a lot of it was written from scratch.
称为segal ds 这是系统r的残余 但很多都是从零开始编写的
Sequel.
续集
Ds is still around.
DS还在
They renamed it to db two,
他们将其重命名为DB 2
just like dv two for vse there's some like mainframe system that they wrote
就像VSE的DV 2一样
sql ds four.
还有一些类似于他们编写的SQL DS 4的大型机系统
There's five versions of db two.
DB 2有五个版本
It's hard to track of them.
很难追踪他们
But then what we know about what we consider db two today,
但是我们今天所知道的DB 2
that first came out in 1983.
第一次出现是在1983年
When this came out 83,
当它在83年问世时
this is sort of the shot across the bow in the database industry to say,
这是数据库行业的一次尝试
now ibm series by the relational model.
现在是IBM系列的关系模型
These is a real idea.
这是一个真实的想法
Ingress and oracle are already still in the marketplace.
Ingress和Oracle仍然在市场上
But it basically showed that the relation model is the way forward.
但它基本上表明 关系模式是前进的方向
And sequel became the defective standard when this came out in 83.
当这本书在83年出版时 续集成为了有缺陷的标准
And oracle was at the right place at the right time,
甲骨文在正确的时间出现在了正确的地方
because I when ibm ibm was not going to say they were the juggernaut
因为当IBM的时候
in the commuting industry.
IBM不会说他们是通勤行业的巨头
So they said, hey, this is the way it's going to be.
所以他们说 嘿 事情就是这样的
This is the language we're going to use.
这就是我们要用的语言
Everyone said that ibm says that's what I do.
每个人都说IBM说这就是我所做的
When oracle was there, we say, hey, we already support sequel.
当甲骨文在那里的时候 我们说 嘿 我们已经支持Sequel了
We're going to go.
我们要走了
Ingress had its own programming language called quell.
Ingress有自己的编程语言Quell
That strong breaker still claims is better than sql.
那个强大的破坏者仍然声称比SQL更好
They eventually supported sequel,
他们最终支持了
but it was by the time they added it, it was too late.
《续集》 但当他们加入时 已经太晚了
So sequel reasonably spelled as seqeul because it's supposed to be
所以Sequel合理地拼写为Seqeul
the sequel to quell.
因为它应该是Quell的续集
Right?
对的
To play on words,
玩文字游戏
then they got sued for trademark enrichment,
然后他们因为商标丰富而被起诉
so then they renamed it to sql and then there was a standard body to figure
所以他们把它改名为SQL
out what should be the programming language we use
然后有一个标准机构来确定我们应该使用什么编程语言
for relational databases.
对于关系数据库
And supposedly they were going to use quell,
据推测 他们将使用奎尔
set a sequel,
设置一个续集
but dome breaker didn't like standards bodies and decided not to submit
但穹顶破坏者不喜欢标准机构
any paperwork for quell.
并决定不为奎尔提交任何文件
So there's this paragraph here from the larry ellison.
这是拉里·埃里森的一段话
Unauthorized biography.
未经授权的传记
I don't want you to recall it,
我不想让你回忆起它
but it came out in the late 90s where they basically talked about how they
但它出现在90年代末
thought quell was better than sql,
他们基本上是在谈论他们如何认为Quell比SQL更好
but mike hated standards body.
但Mike讨厌标准机构
So he didn't submit anything.
所以他没有提交任何东西
Anyway.
无论如何
So that's why we end up with a sequel instead of quell.
所以这就是为什么我们最终选择了续集而不是《平息》
Does this one on hacker news occasionally see like people say, hey,
这个在黑客新闻上偶尔会看到人们说
i've better the new version of sequel or better version of a sequel.
嘿 我有更好的新版本的续集或更好的版本的续集
And they a lot of the things they end up fixing the problems with in sequel
他们最终在续集中解决了很多问题
like having the front claws after the select clause like quell.
比如在选择条款之后有前爪 比如quell
Already did that in the 70s.
在70年代已经这样做了
But we ended up with a sequel.
但我们最终还是拍了续集
Sorry.
抱歉
Right?
对的
So oracle basically wins the crown during the 1980s.
所以甲骨文基本上在20世纪80年代赢得了桂冠
There's a bunch of other startups that come along that do relation databases.
还有很多其他的创业公司也在做关系数据库
Psi based on formics interface,
PSI基于FORMICS接口
terror data was a data warehouse tandem got bought by deck.
Terror Data是DECK收购的数据仓库串联
Basically, the only one that's still thriving today, I would say,
基本上 我想说的是 今天唯一还在蓬勃发展的是oracle和db two
is oracle and db two and thriving is not the right word I all these
而“蓬勃发展”这个词并不恰当
like psi based still makes a ton of money.
因为所有这些都是基于psi的 但仍然赚了很多钱
But again, if you're a new start up a new company,
但是 如果你是一家新成立的公司 你不会使用它
you wouldn't use it a lot of these systems are still arrayed maintenance mode,
很多系统仍然处于维护模式
but oracle is being actively loved,
但甲骨文是积极的爱
and then same with db two tear data is they're getting crushed by snowflake.
然后与db two tear数据一样 他们正在被雪花粉碎
So stone breaker,
所以破石者 他商业化了他的入口
he commercialized his ingress,
回到伯克利
goes back to berkeley, starts a new day system called postgress.
开始了一个新的一天系统 叫做postgress
If you're the one I postgress is called postgres because it's post ingress.
如果你是我 Postgress被称为Postgres 因为它是Post Ingress
It's the sense that he built after ingress.
这是他在进入后建立的感觉
And instead of being a relational data system,
他称这个系统为对象关系数据库系统
he called this thing as an object relational database system.
而不是关系数据系统
Because object oriented program was the hot thing in the 1980s.
因为面向对象编程是20世纪80年代的热门话题
And this is why they postcards were designed for the very
这就是为什么明信片一开始就被设计得
beginning to be very extensible.
非常可扩展
You can have user defined types, user defined functions, and so forth,
你可以有用户定义的类型
because they wanted to borrow some of the ideas of object oriented databases,
用户定义的函数等等 因为他们想借用面向对象数据库的一些想法
which would be the next slide and be able to extend postcards very easily.
这将是下一张幻灯片 并且能够很容易地扩展明信片
Even today, technically,
即使在今天
postcards is an object based on database system.
从技术上讲 明信片也是一个基于数据库系统的对象
People mostly ignore this part,
人们大多忽略了这一部分
the object part.
客体部分
Where are we at so far?
到目前为止我们在哪里
1970s, kodaso?
20世纪70年代 科达索
Is there cobalt that the cobalt way to program davis is their glacial model
有没有钴
comes out?
用钴来编程戴维斯是他们的冰川模型出来了
People say hit is the bad idea.
人们说打人是个坏主意
Coda cell is the right way to do it,
尾波细胞是正确的方法
especially where some model wins.
尤其是在一些模型获胜的情况下
And there's all these ways from davis has come out in the 1980s,
戴维斯的所有这些方法都是在20世纪80年代出现的
early 1980s,
80年代初
10 years later after that,
10年后
then we end up with these object, ordinary databases.
我们最终得到了这些对象 普通数据库
And what i'm saying where people come along every 10 years and say,
我想说的是 每隔10年
I have a better idea.
人们就会说 我有一个更好的主意
In the 1980s,
在20世纪80年代 人们认识到
people recognize that if application available is going to use
如果应用程序可用
an object oriented programming language.
就要使用面向对象的编程语言
Like c plus is the hot thing in the late 1980s,
就像C+是20世纪80年代末的热门话题一样
that there was this impedance mismatch,
存在这种阻抗不匹配
where the way the database system represented data as relations did not map
即数据库系统将数据表示为关系的方式没有清晰地映射到
cleanly into how objects or object oriented programming represented data.
对象或面向对象编程表示数据的方式
So you'd have to write these sql queries that would basically convert rows
因此 您必须编写这些sql查询
into now objects,
这些查询基本上会将行转换为now对象
sort of nested hierarchies.
类似于嵌套层次结构
And so a bunch of companies said this is kind of stupid.
所以很多公司说这有点愚蠢
Would it be distorted the objects directly in the database as objects?
数据库中的对象直接作为对象会被扭曲吗
There's a couple of systems, versant objects or 02.
有几个系统 Versant Objects或02
I think mark logic you actually just got bought a few weeks ago,
我认为马克的逻辑实际上是你几周前才被买下的
but they were late 90s.
但他们是90年代末的
And so a bunch of these systems don't exist anymore again.
所以一堆这样的系统再也不存在了
Are there a maintenance mode?
是否有维护模式
The what killed him was that there was no standard query language you
杀死他的是没有标准的查询语言
could use for object oriented databases.
你可以使用面向对象的数据库
Eventually, they propose oql the object query language,
最终 他们提出了对象查询语言oql
but nobody supported that.
但没有人支持它
It was too late.
已经太迟了
Basically,
基本上
the problem was because you had this tight coupling
这个问题是因为你在数据库系统
between the database system and the programming language.
和编程语言之间有这种紧密耦合
It made your application less portable.
它降低了应用程序的可移植性
It wasn't very easy for you to switch to another object oriented database system,
对你来说 切换到另一个面向对象的数据库系统并不容易
because you were writing to their proprietary api similar to how ims
因为你正在编写他们的专有api
exposed a proprietor api to their internal data structures.
类似于ims如何将所有者api暴露给他们的内部数据结构
So now sequel is supposed to be a standard course for basic queries.
所以现在Sequel应该是基本查询的标准课程
You can easily switch them from monday to such another.
你可以很容易地把它们从星期一换到另一个星期一
Every bidder has the realm of proprietary extensions.
每个投标人都拥有专有扩展领域
So even though there is a standard,
所以即使有一个标准
it isn't,
不是的
there isn't a universal standard that everyone follows.
没有一个人人都遵守的通用标准
So you can make the same argument about sequel today.
所以你今天可以对续集提出同样的论点
Or m's hide a lot of this.
或者我隐瞒了很多
Here's what it looks like.
这是它的样子
Say.
说
We have a application code.
我们有一个应用代码
We want to store student information.
我们想要存储学生信息
The student has an ida name, an email address,
学生有一个ida名称 一个电子邮件地址
and then a potential list of phone numbers.
然后是一个可能的电话号码列表
The way you would represent potentially represent this
在纯关系模型中
in a pure relational model,
即只有标量值的情况下
meaning where there's only scalar values.
您可能会表示这种方式
You'd have to have a student table,
你必须有一张学生桌
and then a student phone table.
然后是一张学生电话桌
So that now, if I want in my programming language,
所以现在 如果我想在我的编程语言中
if I want to instantiate this object,
如果我想实例化这个对象
I would have to do a look up where I either first query the the student
我必须做一个查找 我要么首先查询学生 然后进行第二次查询
and then do a second query to go get all the phone
以获得所有的电话号码
numbers or do a join and then make sure I throw
或者做一个连接
away the the redundant student information.
然后确保我扔掉多余的学生信息
I when I give the result back.
当我给回结果的时候
Again, the object oriented basis guy would say this is stupid,
再次 面向对象的基础家伙会说这是愚蠢的
object oriented.
面向对象的
People say this is stupid.
人们说这很愚蠢
Just store the the nested objects together in a single record.
只需将嵌套对象一起存储在单个记录中
And now it's only one fetch to the davis as one read call to go bring
现在 只需对davis进行一次fetch
this data in.
就像进行一次read调用以将此数据带入一样
So the problem with this, though,
问题是
is for a simple example,
对于一个简单的例子 有一个1对1的通信程序
there's like a 1 to 1 correspondence routine,
一个学生的电话号码
a student phone number, and the student sure this is probably fine.
学生确定这可能是好的
In fact,
事实上
in modern relations data systems,
在现代关系数据系统中
you could store the phone number as an array of strings.
您可以将电话号码存储为字符串数组
Most systems will support that.
大多数系统都支持这一点
The trouble is now when you go back to that part supplier issue,
现在的问题是 当您回到零件供应商问题时
if you now start embedding or de normalizing the all the parts
如果您现在开始嵌入或取消标准化供应商提供的所有零件
that a supplier supplies and put them into the supplier record,
并将其放入供应商记录中
then I have that problem.
那么我就会遇到这个问题
Or if I need an updated field,
或者如果我需要更新的字段
I have duplicate information.
我有重复的信息
My application code needs to make sure all that's in sync.
我的应用程序代码需要确保所有的同步
I I I don't update some of the records, but not all of them.
我不更新一些记录 但不是全部
Doing complex joins,
执行复杂连接
make sure you have data integrity,
确保数据完整性
becomes problematic in in this approach.
在这种方法中是有问题的
And i'm saying there's some cases where you do want to store jason.
我要说的是 在某些情况下 你确实想要存储Jason
And again,
再一次
there are progress other day systems that will have a jason type.
有一些进步 其他的白天系统将会有一个贾森类型
And the the methods to store jason data in a binary form
以及以二进制形式高效存储贾森数据（而不仅仅是文本）的
efficiently instead of just text.
方法
Mogadi does this, they have their own base on data type.
Mogadi做到了这一点 他们有自己的数据类型基础
Postcards have something similar.
明信片也有类似的东西
Again, a lot of the ideas that were done in these specialized systems.
同样 很多想法都是在这些专门的系统中完成的
So these non relational systems have now found their way into relational systems.
所以这些非关系系统现在已经找到了进入关系系统的方法
All right.
好吧
Then the 1990s I called the boring days,
然后
there wasn't any sort of radical change to the harvard landscape
在我称之为“无聊的日子”的20世纪90年代
or the workload landscape.
哈佛的格局或工作量格局没有任何根本性的变化
Right?
对的
There wasn't it wasn't like the advent of the cloud or or microcomputers
它不像20世纪80年代出现的云或微型计算机
in the 1980s,
就像事情正在发生
which is like things are going along, things are getting better.
事情正在变得更好
Harbor is getting better, the data sets are getting bigger,
港湾正在变得更好
but it wasn't dramatic change.
数据集正在变得更大 但这并不是戏剧性的变化
Right?
对的
So I think the sort of four major events would be
所以我认为四个主要事件
microsoft bought aa copy or license to the sigh of a source code,
是微软购买了一个源代码的副本或许可证
forks it, and then they create sql server.
然后创建了sql server
Segal server supports t sequel,
Segal服务器支持T Sequel
which is their variance sequel that comes from side base,
这是来自Side Base的变体Sequel
side base invented t sequel.
Side Base发明了T Sequel
At this point again,
在这一点上
segal server is state of the art side base is in maintenance mode.
西格尔服务器是最先进的 基地是在维护模式
I don't know how much of the original sideways code is
我不知道有多少原始的sideways代码
still a sequel celebrity these days.
仍然是这些天的续集名人
They did major rewrites in 2000.
他们在2000年进行了重大重写
They did major rereads in 1998 and in 2006.
他们在1998年和2006年进行了大量重读
My sequel sort of get there's a guy in these finland
我的续集有点像芬兰的一个人开始重写或开始编写
started rewriting or started writing his own data system to replace
自己的数据系统来取代m sequel
m sequel and called it my sequel.
并称其为我的续集
My is the name of his daughter.
我是他女儿的名字
He also did marie db that's his other daughter.
他还做了玛丽DB 那是他的另一个女儿
Then a a he has a son named max,
然后他有一个儿子叫马克斯
and there is max db like he names all his davis after his kids.
还有马克斯db 就像他用他的孩子的名字给他所有的戴维斯命名一样
Postgres get recently started as an academic project.
Postgres最近开始作为一个学术项目
Strawburger loved quell in the 1980s when they first started writing it.
在20世纪80年代 当他们第一次开始写这本书的时候 斯特劳伯格很喜欢奎尔
It was used 12.
它被用了12次
But then in 95,
但在95
90 62 grad students took the original academic source code,
9062名研究生采用了原始的学术源代码
and then convert it to make it actually support sql.
然后对其进行转换 使其真正支持sql
And that's why it's called progress ql they might know what
这就是为什么它被称为Progress QL
the original programming language process was written in the 1980s.
他们可能知道最初的编程语言Process是在20世纪80年代编写的
Let me take a guess.
让我猜一下
This is cobalt.
这是钴
No.
不
Abby can close it.
艾比可以关上它
Did you take a lisp?
你口齿不清吗
It was the 80s, right?
那是80年代 对吧
Cocaine or whatever like.
可卡因之类的
And then they realized that was a bad idea.
然后他们意识到这是个坏主意
So then they had a compiler convert the lisp into c and compile that.
然后他们让一个编译器将Lisp转换成C并编译它
And then that was a bad idea.
那是个坏主意
They rewrote everything in c and then sequel light started early 2000.
他们用C语言重写了所有的东西 然后在2000年初开始了续集之光
It's one dude invented this down in north carolina,
这是北卡罗来纳州的一个家伙发明的
richard hip.
他叫理查德·希普
He still looked the main program on the senate.
他仍然关注参议院的主要计划
The one thing that did change,
我想说的是
I would say, was not a dramatic change,
有一件事确实发生了变化
is that people started to realize,
但并不是戏剧性的变化
I don't just want to use my data system to transactions and ingest new data.
那就是人们开始意识到 我不想只是使用我的数据系统来处理和接收新数据
Someone want to start doing analytics,
有人想开始做分析
start extrapolate new information business.
开始推断新的信息业务
Intelligent decision support has a bunch of different names.
智能决策支持有很多不同的名称
All these systems at the time are all row stores.
当时所有这些系统都是行存储
And as we know,
正如我们所知
running analytical queries on a row store is highly inefficient.
在行存储上运行分析查询的效率非常低
There was this optimization technique called data cubes where you
有一种叫做数据立方体的优化技术
basically figure like materialized view,
你基本上就像物化视图一样
where you pre computed these multi conventional arrays
你预先计算这些不同
of different group i's and aggregation and so forth.
组的多个常规阵列和聚合等等
And you would pre compete and you run your analytics on those.
你会在比赛前运行你的分析
Nobody uses data cubes today because column stores so much faster.
现在没有人使用数据立方体 因为列存储的速度要快得多
But this is how people got by in the 1990s.
但这就是上世纪90年代人们的生活方式
So the big game changer, though,
因此
was in 2000s when the internet comes along.
最大的游戏规则改变者是2000年代互联网的出现
So again, prior to this,
所以 在此之前
when you think about it who had big databases,
当你想到谁拥有大数据库时
the big bangs, walmart's, right?
大爆炸 沃尔玛 对吧
The only like the fortune 500 companies had big data as problems.
只有财富500强公司才有大数据问题
But when the internet comes along,
但当互联网出现时
it doesn't take that much for a small number of people to put something
一小部分人把东西放到互联网上
on the internet and have a lot of people start using the application
让很多人开始使用网站的应用程序
of the website.
这并不需要太多时间
And you start generating a lot of traffic and a lot of data,
你开始产生大量的流量和数据
a lot of users.
大量的用户
Right?
对的
So this was a big change in how people approach databases in the 2000.
所以这是2000年人们如何处理数据库的一个巨大变化
But at the time,
但在当时
all of the sort of the commercial enterprise databases were very heavyweight,
所有的商业企业数据库都是重量级的 比如oracle
oracle, db two, cyprus, they were very expensive.
db two cyprus 它们都非常昂贵
And then the open source databases that we think about today,
然后我们今天想到的开源数据库
postcards and my sql,
明信片和我的SQL
they were pretty primitive back in the day.
它们在过去是非常原始的
My sequel to support transactions until inter db came along,
我的续篇支持事务
2003 2004.
直到2003年和2004年Inter DB出现
So what people ended up doing was writing out their own sort
因此
of custom middleware to route queries to these single node database
人们最终要做的是编写自己的自定义中间件
indices.
将查询路由到这些单节点数据库索引
So they would sort of treat my sql as like a dumb key value store,
所以他们会把我的SQL当作一个哑键值存储
and then have something in front of it to route queries to different shards
然后在它前面有一些东西来将查询路由到不同的碎片
that the idea is still widely used today,
这个想法至今仍被广泛使用
but the people were wrong on their own back.
但人们自己错了
Then.
然后
The other thing that happened was,
发生的另一件事是
again, as I say,
正如我所说的
it doesn't take that much to start collecting a lot of data.
开始收集大量数据并不需要那么多时间
More people started wanting to analyze this data.
更多的人开始想要分析这些数据
Then we realize or they realize that the sort
然后我们意识到
of general purpose data systems at a row store that tries to do
或者他们意识到
transactions and analytics.
行存储中的通用数据系统试图进行交易和分析
Was that bad idea?
这是个坏主意吗
And people started building these custom analytical data systems,
人们开始建立这些定制的分析数据系统
which again,
will be the the sort of key idea that we're focusing on this semester.
这也将是我们这学期关注的关键思想
A lot of these were distributed and shared nothing of us.
其中很多都是分发的 我们没有分享任何东西
All of these were going to be actually all
所有这些实际上都是关系和SQL
of these were relational and sql most of them are forks of post graphs.
其中大多数都是POST图的分支
And they're going to store the database as column stores.
他们将把数据库存储为列存储
Again, seems like an obvious idea now.
再一次 现在似乎是一个显而易见的想法
And because the wind you get from are so significant,
因为你得到的风是如此重要
back then this was unheard of,
这在当时是闻所未闻的
It's not unheard of it, because the ideas from the 70s,
这不是闻所未闻的
but like having these explicitly stored,
因为70年代的想法
the ideas columns that was novel,
但就像这些明确存储的想法专栏是新颖的
that was a game changer.
这是游戏规则的改变者
So the sort of the main systems at this time are listed here.
所以这里列出了目前主要系统的种类
So natzisa was a fork a postgrasse,
因此 natzisa是postgrasse的一个分支
but they put a fpga down to the storage layer to make it run filters faster.
但他们将fpga放到存储层 使其更快地运行滤波器
Park sells a fork of postcards,
帕克出售一大堆明信片
distributed version postgres.
分发版Postgres
This is actually what redshift is redshift.
这就是所谓的红移
They bought a license to park cell.
他们买了停车许可证
Didn't really make any changes, just slapped it up and called it redshift.
并没有真正做任何改变 只是把它拍起来 并称之为红移
Was that this is not a secret.
这不是秘密
I was telling you, all right, this is public.
我告诉你 好吧 这是公开的
And so just threw it up.
所以就吐了出来
It made so much money.
它赚了这么多钱
Now we've got to start making this real.
现在我们必须开始让这一切成为现实
Right?
对的
And it's been written many times over vertica.
它在Vertica上被写了很多次
That's a company that started by my advisers,
这是一家由我的顾问迈克·斯
mike stone breaker, and then santa zonatic.
通·布雷克和圣佐纳蒂克创办的公司
That's a fork, a postgres.
那是一把叉子 一把叉子
Data leg row was a shorter version of ingress.
Data Leg Row是Ingress的较短版本
And the green plum is a fork and postgres mode adb was
青梅是一个叉子
exactly the other one here that was written from scratch.
而Postgres模式ADB正是另一个从零开始编写的模式
And that came out of cwi the same.
从CWI出来的也是一样
Have you ever heard of ducky b it's the same research group that made
你听说过ducky b吗 它是制作mode adb.
mode adb dot db was originally called mode db light.
db的同一个研究小组 最初被称为mode db light
It was a fork mode db to run embedded in like our programs.
这是一个分叉模式的数据库 可以像我们的程序一样嵌入运行
And then they rewrote it and ended up being doug db i'm not sure I
然后他们重写了它 最后变成了道格db
may have to bleed this.
我不确定我可能要流这个血
I'm not sure this is public.
我不确定这是公开的
Microsoft bought data, microsoft bought data, leg grow,
微软买了数据 微软买了数据 leg grow
ibm bought the teaser park sell.
ibm买了teaser park sell
They can never get bought that.
他们永远不会被收买
He's got and i'm getting licensed.
他有 我也有执照
I think the company's dead vertica got acquired by hp any of you
我认为公司的死亡vertica被惠普收购了
got never bought and then green palm got bought by
你们中的任何一个都没有被收购 然后green palm被收购了
no emc hold on.
没有EMC 请稍候
At some point, there were miemc it's hard to keep track of this.
在某种程度上 有miemc很难跟踪这一点
They got bought.
他们被收买了
And then they divested it off to an emc in order to take back.
然后他们将其剥离给EMC 以便收回
Emc had a database piece.
EMC有一个数据库部分
Vmr had a database piece.
VMR有一个数据库片段
They took it out, and they formed a new company called pivotal.
他们把它拿出来 成立了一家名为Pivotal的新公司
It was green palm and then sequel fire or gem fire,
它是绿色棕榈 然后是续集火或宝石火
which I think that notes emc bought them,
我认为注意到EMC购买了它们
vm ware bought sql file.
VM Ware购买了SQL文件
They took them out, made pivotal,
他们把它们拿出来
and then bmr bought pivotal.
做了pivotal 然后bmr收购了pivotal
It's so data leg row got up with microsoft.
所以数据腿排和微软站在了一起
It was a hacked up version of charted ingress.
这是海图入口的一个破解版本
And I think they paid money for it.
我想他们为此付了钱
And then after they bought it,
然后在他们买了它之后
so after they wrote the check,
所以在他们写了支票之后
then they had their technical people actually look at it and say this is
他们让他们的技术人员看了看
all crap.
然后说这都是废话
We can't use any of this and they threw it all away.
我们不能用这些东西 他们把它们都扔了
They made them they end up running the sequel server data warehouse
他们最终从头开始运行Sequel服务器数据仓库
from scratch the parallel data warehouse instead of using any
并行数据仓库
of these garbage.
而不是使用这些垃圾
There's another one too.
还有一个
I'm missing astor data they were bought by.
我错过了他们购买的阿斯特数据
They were bought, I think by terror data.
我想他们是被恐怖数据收买的
The while all this work is happening on these parallel column store data warehouses,
虽然所有这些工作都是在这些并行列存储数据仓库上进行的
there was this other big trend of these matte reduced systems.
但还有另一个大趋势 即这些减少了遮罩的系统
Again,
再一次
so what it's been 10 years now since the object ordinary databases were
自从普通数据库的对象是一个坏主意以来
a bad idea,
已经过去了10年
now we're 10 years later, so this thing comes along from google.
现在我们已经10年了 所以这个东西来自谷歌
They built a custom execution engine with this map,
他们用这个地图建立了一个自定义的执行引擎
reduce programming model that to help them crawl their to build the index
减少了编程模型
for the web crawl.
以帮助他们抓取他们的建立索引的网页抓取
And they end up using for a bunch of other data processing tasks
他们最终将其用于其他数据处理任务或分析
or analytical tasks.
任务
So google put out the paper,
所以谷歌发布了这篇论文 说
say, hey, that's what we're using.
嘿 这就是我们正在使用的
The pi still happens now,
PI现在仍在发生
but google was really the super hot thing in the 2000s.
但谷歌在2000年代确实是超级热门的东西
Right?
对的
Anything they did, any paper they put out,
他们所做的任何事情 他们发表的任何论文
people did end up go and re implement themselves,
人们最终都会去重新实现自己
because they thought google is making a ton of money,
因为他们认为谷歌赚了一大笔钱
because they have all these custom systems.
因为他们拥有所有这些定制系统
Let's go build our own custom system too.
让我们也去建立我们自己的自定义系统
Right?
对的
Like h base is a clone a big table,
就像H Base是一个大表的克隆
cause cassandra is a clone a big table and dynamo db that's the acfs dude
因为Cassandra是一个大表的克隆
was the clone of matt reduce.
而Dynamo DB是ACFS的Dude是Matt Reduce的克隆
So google put that map reduce paper.
所以谷歌把地图减少了纸
Yahoo says, see, that says a good idea.
雅虎说 看 这是个好主意
We can use it too.
我们也可以用它
They wrote their own open source version called duke.
他们编写了自己的开源版本 名为Duke
And the basic idea was that you'd write these user defined functions
基本的想法是
like a map and reduce a shuffle phase cover later on next class.
你可以像写地图一样写这些用户定义的函数 并在下一节课上减少洗牌阶段
Instead of using a sequel, you'd write these custom functions.
您可以编写这些自定义函数 而不是使用Sequel
And you just submit them to the davis to the map reduce or do framework
您只需将它们提交给davis 再提交给map reduce或do框架
and run them for you.
然后为您运行它们
It takes us back to the 1970s where the programmer had to define what
它把我们带回了20世纪70年代
the data model actually was or the data they were processing.
那时程序员必须定义数据模型或他们正在处理的数据
There's no sequel at the time of these systems.
在这些系统的时候没有续集
You had to literally write all parts,
你必须从字面上写所有的部分
the i'm going to parse this csv file,
我要解析这个CSV文件
and I expect them to have these columns.
我希望他们有这些列
And you would write that explicit citations in your in the program encoder
你可以在这些函数的程序编码器中写下明确的
in these functions.
引文
So this was the hot thing in the late 2000.
所以这是2000年末的热门话题
That was like this is the way to do this.
这就像是这样做的方式
You ought to add up.
你应该加起来
And then stone breaker,
然后破石者
and then this other guy who does invented a lot of the first pillow databases,
然后另一个发明了很多第一个枕头数据库的人 发表了一篇文章
put out an article that said this is a bad idea.
说这是一个坏主意
Then ii wrote a paper at them and showed it was.
然后我给他们写了一篇论文 证明它是
And then people eventually realize it, turns out the old guys are right.
然后人们最终意识到这一点 事实证明老家伙们是对的
This is a bad idea.
这是个坏主意
So then they try to put sequel on top of map,
所以他们试图把续集放在地图上
reduce facebook invented hive.
减少Facebook发明的蜂巢
And there's a thing called map rdb at a map r which I I think they're dead now.
在地图R上有一个叫做地图RDB的东西 我想他们现在已经死了
But then it turned out that was super inefficient and super slow,
但后来发现这是超级低效和超级缓慢的
because the way just sort of the way her dude was actually implemented,
因为她的家伙实际上是如何实现的
or I don't know exactly how the map arts framework actually worked,
或者我不知道地图艺术框架实际上是如何工作的
but the way they were sort of storing these checkpoints
但他们在查询的每一个阶段存储这些检查点的
at every single stage of the query was super inefficient.
方式是超级低效的
And so all this got thrown away.
所以这一切都被抛弃了
I i've still exists.
我我仍然存在
But like people realize a this is actually a bad idea.
但就像人们意识到这实际上是一个坏主意
As a you want a parallel to the warehouse,
因为你想要一个类似于仓库的东西
you want the thing that we were shown before.
你想要我们之前看到的东西
But it again took 10 years for people to realize this.
但人们又花了10年时间才意识到这一点
This was a bad idea.
这是个坏主意
Also related to, I won't say bad ideas here too,
同样相关的是 我不会在这里说不好的想法
but there was this no sequel movement again,
但又有了这个没有续集的运动
I think brought upon by google and the big table paper basically said,
我认为是由谷歌带来的
hey, the the racial model is bad.
大桌子上的纸基本上说 嘿 种族模式是不好的
The sequel is too slow for modern web application.
对于现代Web应用程序来说 Sequel太慢了
We don't need transactions, we don't need joints.
我们不需要交易 我们不需要关节
We want to build these systems from scratch,
我们想从头开始建立这些系统
right?
对吗
Because you have to understand like if you're building a website,
因为您必须了解
you want to think up 2047 a in a database systems transactions that
如果您正在构建一个网站
maybe didn't have
您需要在数据库系统事务中考虑2047个事务
backups or replicas for high availability.
这些事务可能没有备份或副本以实现高可用性
That means if no goes down,
这意味着如果没有宕机
if your whole website goes down, that's bad, you lose money.
如果你的整个网站宕机 那很糟糕 你会赔钱
So the no sequel guys facing said, well,
所以没有续集的人说
maybe you were to let the system maybe have corrupt data
好吧 也许你要让系统可能有损坏的数据
or not strictly follow transaction semantics,
或者不严格遵循事务语义
transport in exchange for always being up, always being online.
传输以换取始终启动 始终在线
So there's a bunch of these systems that got built.
所以有很多这样的系统被建造出来
Under this model,
在这种模式下
some things sometimes is dynamite.
有些事情有时是爆炸性的
Db was built by amazon for the shopping cart.
DB是亚马逊为购物车打造的
If I put some in my shopping cart, it maybe disappears.
如果我把一些放进购物车 它可能会消失
This is the end of the world,
这是世界末日
probably not.
可能不会
If I put something in my bank account and disappears, that's a big problem.
如果我在银行账户里存了钱 然后消失了 那就是个大问题
Right?
对的
So all these systems basically follow different looser semantics over what
因此 所有这些系统基本上都遵循不同的松散语义
the traditional relational transaction,
而传统的关系事务
strongly consistent daily systems would follow to varying degrees of success.
强一致性日常系统则遵循不同的成功程度
And as I said before,
正如我之前所说
basically everybody supports segal now, except for retis,
现在基本上每个人都支持segal 除了retis
I think raven db they all have their own version of sql
我认为raven db他们都有自己的sql版本 但它基本上是sql
but it's basically sql without wanting to say it react as dead.
不想说它的反应是死的
So there I don't I don't think we have any and then oracle new sequel I
所以 我不认为我们有任何
think it's just perfectly to be under the covers at the same time.
然后甲骨文新的续集 我认为这是完美的 在同一时间被掩盖
All right, so soon after the no sequel databases got popular,
好吧 在“无续集”数据库流行后不久
there was another movement called new sequel.
就出现了另一个运动 叫做“新续集”
This one I was involved in where the idea was that you wouldn't have
我参与的这个项目的想法是
the same high scalability and performance of a no sql database system.
您不会拥有与无SQL数据库系统相同的高可伸缩性和性能
But without giving up transactions,
但在不放弃交易的情况下
obviously, you can't,
显然 你不能
you can't go faster than the speed of light.
你不可能超过光速
So if you have machines in different areas of the world,
因此 如果你在世界的不同地区都有机器
you can't make that go faster,
你不能让它运行得更快
but you at least make sure that things are correct.
但你至少要确保事情是正确的
So all the systems that came out under this no segal movement,
因此 除了odb map c之外 所有在“无Segal ”
with maybe the exception of of odb map c will get renamed to a sequel store,
运动下推出的系统都将重命名为sequel store
and they wouldn't necessarily call themselves a new sql system now.
并且它们现在不一定会称自己为新的sql系统
And then spanner did detail.
然后扳手做了细节
Spanner is still here.
扳手还在这里
Spanner is legit.
扳手是合法的
But for the most part,
但在大多数情况下
bunch of things you've never heard of before the trans lattice,
在trans lattice之前
i'm sure nobody's heard of gddb they all pretty much failed.
你从来没有听说过很多东西 我敢肯定没有人听说过gddb 他们几乎都失败了
Foundation db had a sequel there that was kind of crap.
DB基金会在那里有一个续集 那是一种垃圾
Apple bought down, threw that away.
苹果买下了 扔掉了
And they since open source it,
他们已经开源了它
but it's not used as a relational data system with sequel.
但它没有被用作Sequel的关系数据系统
Now.
现在
What did happen though?
但发生了什么
All a bunch of these systems didn't pan out.
所有这些系统都没有成功
The new transaction data systems aren't actually getting some traction,
新的交易数据系统实际上并没有得到一些牵引力
and these sort of fall under the umbrella of distributed sequel.
而这些都属于分布式Sequel的范畴
Instead of calling new sql was sort of vague,
而不是调用新的SQL是一种模糊的
you say it's a derivative sql system.
你说它是一个衍生的SQL系统
Tide eb is out of china.
浪潮EB退出中国
Cochrane eb is probably raised the most money of all these.
科克伦EB可能是所有这些中筹集资金最多的
And then you go by as another startup that's based on postgraduate.
然后你就变成了另一家基于研究生的创业公司
The com, db two was built by, I think, bloomberg.
我认为 COM DB Two是由Bloomberg建立的
I've never heard anybody use the com db two outside of bloomberg,
我从来没有听说过有人在彭博以外的地方使用com db 2
but it is absurd, so it doesn't exist.
但这是荒谬的 所以它并不存在
So the main take away here is that these systems,
所以这里主要的收获是这些系统
these systems are going against the conventional wisdom that like you want
这些系统违背了传统智慧
an original model,
就像你想要一个原始模型一样
you want to sequel one in transactions.
你想要在交易中继续一个
Because all the new sequel systems are hot.
因为所有新的续集系统都很热门
By the time that people realized I do want sequel, I do want transactions,
当人们意识到我确实想要续集时 我确实想要交易
they failed or didn't pan out.
他们失败了或者没有成功
Then these systems were the right place at the right time building
然后这些系统在正确的时间出现在正确的地方
off the things that the earlier systems had done finishing up.
建立在早期系统已经完成的东西之上
We have cloud systems.
我们有云系统
Again, we'll cover this a lot throughout the semester.
同样 我们将在整个学期中对此进行大量讨论
Basically, now the harbor that escape has changed.
基本上 现在逃离的港湾已经改变了
People are no longer running on pram.
人们不再在婴儿车上奔跑
You're now running in a cloud,
您现在正在云中运行
right?
是吧
And that means your resources can be elastic.
这意味着你的资源是有弹性的
You don't have to go through this long provisioning cycle of like,
您不必经历这种漫长的配置周期
I want to buy these machines and procurement,
例如 我想购买这些机器并进行采购
and it takes a long time to actually get them.
而实际获得它们需要很长时间
With a credit card.
用信用卡
You can spit up a new instance very, very quickly.
您可以非常快速地创建一个新实例
So every initially there was a bunch of these databases
所以最初有一堆服务产品或产品的数据库
of service products or offerings where it would just take
它只会像现成的一样
like off the shelf I sequel rather than avm for you.
而不是AVM
It's before containers rather than avm for you,
对你来说 这是在集装箱之前 而不是在avm之前
and they charge you for that.
他们会向你收费
But it didn't.
但它没有
My sequel wasn't really aware that it's running in the cloud.
我的续集并没有真正意识到它在云中运行
It's just running on some vm but since then,
它只是在一些虚拟机上运行 但从那时起
there's now assessments designed from scratch explicitly for running a a
现在有从零开始设计的评估
in a cloud system.
明确用于在云系统中运行
But we would call these cloud native snowflakes,
但我们会称这些云为原生雪花
probably the most fame in one of all these like they designed
可能是所有这些中最出名的一个
explicitly in the beginning,
就像他们一开始明确设计的那样
not to run on pram, only to run in the cloud.
不在婴儿车上运行 只在云中运行
Then therefore,
因此
you can make certain design choices which will cover next week.
你可以做出某些设计选择 这将涵盖下周
That can take advantage of that.
可以利用这一点
Want to make things also to that.
想做的事也要到那去
Came out of the map produced world plus now with the cloud.
从地图中产生的世界加上现在的云
Are these shared disk systems?
这些是共享磁盘系统吗
Prior to this,
在此之前
the the conventional wisdom of how you would build it and tribute
传统的智慧
a daily system is would be shared nothing.
你将如何建立它和贡品每日系统是不会分享什么
Now with the cloud where amazon or whoever is taking care
现在有了云
of the storage layer for you,
Amazon或任何为您负责存储层的人
you don't want to be able to share nothing system.
你不想什么都不共享系统
You want to use a shared disk system and let the cloud vendor handle
您希望使用共享磁盘系统
the storage for you.
并让云供应商为您处理存储
So there's a bunch of systems now built on top of this shared disk approach.
因此 现在有许多系统都是基于这种共享磁盘方法构建的
This is the fact,
这就是事实
this is how everyone's building modern data systems today.
这就是今天每个人构建现代数据系统的方式
People talk about I have a data lake,
人们谈论我有一个数据湖
right?
对吗
Or we'll see this.
否则我们会看到这个
When we talk about data bricks,
当我们谈论数据砖块时
they're talking about basically serving on s three, right?
他们说的基本上是在S 3上服务 对吗
Something with a shared disk model.
具有共享磁盘模型的东西
Every year I I got to complain about this.
每年我都要抱怨这个
We're at the sort of phase now where it's, again, no sql,
我们现在正处于这样一个阶段
the no sequel women died out.
再一次 没有sql 没有续集的女人消失了
People realize sequel is the way to go still coming along.
人们意识到续集是未来的发展方向
I wouldn't necessarily maybe not necessarily call these new sequel systems,
我不一定会把这些新的sequel系统称为sequel系统 但在过去的5
but they've definitely become more prominent in the last 5 or 6 years
6年里 它们肯定会变得更加突出
Or these graph database systems.
或者这些图形数据库系统
But the idea is that instead of storing your database as relations,
但其思想是不将数据库存储为关系
it's intrinsically, it's a graph.
从本质上讲 它是一个图表
Let me sort it as a graph structure between relations and so forth.
让我把它分类为关系之间的图形结构等等
And this can be either rdf or triple store or property graphs.
这可以是RDF或三元组存储或属性图
It has a bunch of different names.
它有一堆不同的名字
But it's essentially the same thing that they were doing back in the 70s
但本质上
with the kodaso network model.
这与他们在70年代用科达索网络模型所做的事情是一样的
So the big claim is that because you're starting a database
所以最大的声明是
as negatively as graphs.
因为你正在启动一个像图表一样消极的数据库
And because you're now exposing a nato graph api you can be
因为您现在公开了一个NATO图形API
much better than a relational data system.
所以您可以比关系数据系统好得多
We've heard that before.
我们以前听说过
That was the argument for the object oriented databases.
这就是面向对象数据库的论点
It's the object,
它是物体
the jason databases,
贾森数据库
all these people make the same argument.
所有这些人都提出了同样的论点
And so sure there are some times what you do want to traverse your database
当然 有时您确实需要遍历数据库
in a sort of native graph way.
以一种原生图形的方式
But the segal standard is actually adding support for graph queries this year.
但Segal标准今年实际上增加了对图形查询的支持
And it's based on cipher,
它是基于密码的
which was invented by by neo for j so they lose that advantage.
这是由neo为j发明的 所以他们失去了优势
Then now what about the argument that if i'm starting things
那么 如果我以消极的方式开始
negatively as a graph is not going to be better than a relational database?
那么图不会比关系数据库更好 这一论点又如何呢
No,
不
because the paper that came out last week shows that if you built up db you
因为上周发表的一篇论文表明
incorporate some techniques that will help explicitly for graph
如果您构建了数据库 您就会结合一些技术
workloads.
这些技术将明确地帮助图形工作负载
Like multi wave joins,
就像多波加入 我们将在本学期晚些时候介绍
which we will cover a later the semester you cannot perform mu for j
你不能通过10 x dfoj为j执行mu
by ten x dfoj has raised hundreds of millions of dollars.
dfoj已经筹集了数亿美元
Doctor b's like aa small team of people in the netherlands.
B医生就像是荷兰的一个小团队
They beat them at 10:00X and it's a real system.
他们以10:00的速度击败了他们 这是一个真正的系统
It's not just a toy.
它不只是一个玩具
I think graph databases.
我认为图表数据库
We've already see this racial model is absorbing ideas from it.
我们已经看到这种种族模式正在吸收它的思想
I don't see these systems really replacing the the relation of davis is
在我的有生之年
in my lifetime.
我没有看到这些系统真正取代戴维斯的关系
I should have put a speech on.
我应该做个演讲的
Ii made a public bet where in I I made a public bet,
我做了一个公开的赌注 我做了一个公开的赌注
they said in 2020 by 2030,
他们说在2020年到2030年
the graph database market exceeds the racial database market.
图形数据库市场超过了种族数据库市场
I will change my official cmu directory photo to be like so.
我会把我的官方CMU目录照片改成这样
I'm sure when he says I love graph databases and I will use that until I
我敢肯定 当他说我喜欢图表数据库时
die or get fired from seeing you.
我会一直使用它 直到我死了或者因为见到你而被解雇
Ii don't see it happening.
我不认为这会发生
All right.
好吧
So quickly finish up time series databases.
所以很快就完成了时间序列数据库
So these are now newer databases that are designed to store,
因此 现在这些是较新的数据库
telemetry you're collecting or metrics you're collecting from other services,
旨在存储您正在收集的遥测数据或您正在从其他服务
other devices, and so forth.
其他设备等收集的指标
It's relational.
它是关系型的
There's this notion of explicit time ordering and the data you're generating.
有明确的时间顺序和你正在生成的数据的概念
Therefore,
因此
you can design the system to officially take advantage of the domain
您可以将系统设计为正式利用您正在工作的
you're working in.
领域
You wouldn't want to use these for storing arbitrary data.
您不会想要使用它们来存储任意数据
If you have this notion of like ticks or events are showing
如果你有这样的概念
up with some notion of time,
比如滴答声或事件与时间的概念一起出现
anyone do range queries based on those times,
任何人都可以根据这些时间进行范围查询
you could design a system to be more efficient to do this.
你可以设计一个系统来更有效地做到这一点
So probably the three main ones would be time scale,
所以三个主要的可能是时间尺度
which is using extensions on top of post graphs, which is super cool,
这是在后图表之上使用扩展
because you get regular tables and post graphs plus the time series ones.
这是超级酷的 因为你得到了常规的表格和后图表加上时间序列
Influx eb is written from scratch.
流入EB是从头开始编写的
I think they're third rewrite,
我想他们是第三次重写了
but again,
但同样
they're targeting time series of this.
他们的目标是时间序列
Click house is out of russia.
点击房子不在俄罗斯
This is probably when I first learned about click as when you read
这可能是当我第一次了解点击时
the website and all the things that they supported.
当你阅读网站和他们支持的所有东西时
It's a lot of techniques we discussed in the class.
我们在课堂上讨论了很多技巧
It seemed unreal.
这似乎不真实
This is super state of the art.
这是最先进的
The performer summers look amazing.
表演者萨默斯看起来棒极了
My impression, though,
不过 我的印象是 启动和运行并不容易
is that it is it's not easy to get up and running a there's still a lot
还有很多手工工作要做
of manual work you have to do,
但我认为这将
but ii think this one's going to be aa big player.
是一个大玩家
And then prometheus is another big effort in this space.
普罗米修斯是这一领域的另一项重大成就
Last one,
最后一个
block chain devices.
区块链设备
Yes, bit coin.
是的 比特币
If you bought bit coin in 2010.
如果你在2010年买了比特币
Great.
棒极了
Thanks.
谢谢
Congrats.
祝贺
But like people had made claims that like block chain databases are
但就像人们曾经宣称的那样 区块链数据库是
under web three or what everyone call it.
在网络三下 或者大家所说的
This is a radical different way of how you want to build modern applications.
这是构建现代应用程序的一种完全不同的方式
The old way of having these provisioning servers over relational databases
在关系数据库和Sequel上提供这些服务器的旧方法
and sequel and whatever all that stupid you want to build on top
以及你想在区块链数据库上建立的所有愚蠢的东西
of a block chain database to solve all the world's problems.
来解决世界上所有的问题
At the end of the day, what is a block chain?
说到底 什么是区块链
It's just a log.
这只是一根木头
They would call a ledger.
他们会叫账本
It's like, I write ahead log or the pack says log, the state log.
这就像 我提前写日志 或者包说日志 状态日志
Here's all the events or things that are happening to this day of the deeds.
这里是所有的事件或事情正在发生的这一天的行为
Then they had these incremental check sums where the check sum
然后他们有这些增量校验
of a new entry in the log depends on the previous entry of the logs
和其中日志中新条目的校验和依赖于日志中以前的条目
that way.
If you fudge anything below that.
如果你捏造任何低于这个标准的东西
At a previous entry, the check sum doesn't match,
在上一个条目中 校验和不匹配
and you don't have the full data.
并且您没有完整的数据
The technique was invented on merkel treats.
这项技术是在默克尔的零食上发明的
Then now,
然后现在
since you're assuming you're running in a decentralized distributed environment,
因为你假设你在一个分散的分布式环境中运行
we don't trust the people that are reading right into the database.
我们不信任那些直接读入数据库的人
You have to use some visiting fault tolerant or bft protocol to come
你必须使用一些访问容错或BFT协议来达成共识
to consensus to say,
下一个放入日志的条目是什么
what's the next entry which put in a log I it's it's a lot of cool ideas
这是很多很酷的想法
and put together an interesting way,
并以一种有趣的方式组合在一起
but is this game changer now?
但现在这是游戏规则的改变者吗
Right?
对的
I've yet to see a use case that everybody has proposed where a block chain
我还没有看到一个大家都提出的使用案例
would solve a problem that you could not solve
区块链可以解决像postgres这样的传统sql数据库
with a traditional sql database like postgres,
无法解决的问题
or you have some external external issues you have to resolve through like law,
或者你有一些外部的外部问题 你必须通过法律来解决
right?
对吗
Or legal matters.
或法律事务
Right?
对的
So I think there's all garbage.
所以我觉得都是垃圾
These systems here are explicitly doing block chain with a
这里的这些系统在我们的去中心化模型中明确地
in our decentralized model.
用a来做区块链
This is the logo for podb amazon has the worst logos because it's like,
这是podb的标志 亚马逊有最糟糕的标志
unless what is it right?
因为它就像 除非它是对的
Like it.
喜欢它
Qlqldb is our quantum ledger database.
QLQLDB是我们的量子账本数据库
It's not a block chain database where it's like decentralized,
它不是一个区块链数据库 它像去中心化的
like amazon, the trust of authority,
像亚马逊 权威的信任
like you authenticate amazon,
像你认证亚马逊
you don't have to do bfti think they just do two base commit,
你不需要做bfti 他们只需要做两个基本的提交
but you still get that verifiable ledger with the check sums.
但你仍然可以得到可验证的总账和支票总额
As far as they know,
据他们所知
this is not going anywhere they make way more money on selling,
这是不会去任何地方 他们在销售上赚更多的钱
reselling my sequel and postcards as rds or under aurora.
转售我的续集和明信片作为rds或根据极光
Again, I at this point when I first saw these devices,
再次 我在这一点上 当我第一次看到这些设备
but maybe there's something I convinced this is all crap.
但也许有一些东西 我相信这一切都是废话
I was able to say there's no inherent data model to a a block chain database.
我可以说区块链数据库没有固有的数据模型
It's just entries in the log just bytes.
它只是日志中的条目 只是字节
There's some engine above it that has to interpret what those bytes are.
它上面有一些引擎 必须解释这些字节是什么
So it could be a key value store,
所以它可以是一个键值存储
relationship database.
关系数据库
It doesn't matter.
这不重要
There's a bunch of other stuff that should be 2020.
还有一堆其他的东西应该是2020年
So there's a typo.
所以有一个错别字
There's a bunch of other systems,
还有很多其他的系统
categories of things we could talk about embedded databases
我们可以讨论嵌入式数据库
like sequel light and rock cb and duck
比如sequel light和rock cb和duck tb
tb those multi modal or multi model databases where like orangu
这些多模态或多模型数据库 比如orangu tv
tv where you try to support graphs and relations and documents
你可以尝试在一个数据库中支持图形
all in a single one.
关系和文档
In the paper you guys read, we talked about harbor acceleration.
在你们读过的论文中 我们谈到了港口加速
Basically people like the the search for like eldorado,
基本上 人们喜欢寻找埃尔多拉多
the golden city in south america.
南美洲的黄金之城
There's been a search for some kind of hardware for databases for the last 40,
在过去的四五十年里
50 years.
人们一直在寻找某种数据库硬件
It never pans out.
从来没有成功过
People keep trying, but it never works,
人们一直在尝试 但从来没有成功过
but not that it doesn't work.
但并不是说它不起作用
It's just you it never gets the adoption in the market.
它只是你 它永远不会在市场上得到采用
Commodity harbor was always going to win.
商品港总是会赢的
I don't think fpg as or gp us are aa big game changer in the space.
我不认为FPG AS或GP US是该领域的重大游戏规则改变者
Risk five, potentially some interesting stuff.
风险五 可能是一些有趣的东西
But where you're going to see hardware accelerates or databases
但是 只有google
is only going to be from the cloud vendors like google,
amazon和microsoft等云供应商才能提供硬件加速或数据库
amazon, and microsoft, because it at their scale,
因为在他们的规模上
they can justify paying $50 million in development to build up new custom hardware,
他们可以支付5000万美元的开发费用来构建新的定制硬件
because they're going to make so much money and be more efficient for.
因为他们可以赚很多钱 而且效率更高
There are millions of customers.
有数百万的客户
It's very hard to be.
这很难做到
I think it'd be very hard for independent software vendor,
我认为独立软件供应商
independent hardware vendor to break into that market,
独立硬件供应商很难打入这个市场
because either because not only had the design to chip or whatever
因为他们不仅设计了芯片或其他硬件加速器
the hardware accelerator is,
他们还无法说服
they didn't got to go convince some other software company to put it
其他软件公司将其放入自己的数据库中
in their database.
And it never happens.
但从来没有发生过
We didn't really talk about array matrix,
我们并没有真正讨论数组矩阵
and the vector data sets the new buzzword now.
而向量数据现在成为了新的流行词
Because of machine learning,
由于机器学习
there's much of these new nearest neighbor search on vector vectors in new database.
在新的数据库中有许多关于向量的新的最近邻搜索
These have been around for a while,
这些已经存在了一段时间
but the vector ones are new.
但矢量的是新的
I would say this is the only,
我想说的是
as far as I know for now,
据我所知
this is the only type of data you wouldn't actually want to use
这是唯一一种你不想使用关系数据库系统的数据类型
a relational database system for where you want to use
因为你想使用
a specialized system explicitly designed for vectors.
专门为向量设计的系统
Because when you think about it, what if it's a multinational array,
因为当你考虑它时 如果它是一个多国数组
you've got to go traverse it,
你必须遍历它
maybe row wise and column wise and in different dimensions,
可能是按行和按列以及在不同的维度上
and storing that in a table with index columns is a bad idea.
并且将其存储在具有索引列的表中是一个坏主意
So I think we'll see whether the market is big enough to justify needing
因此 我认为我们将看到市场是否足够大
a specialized system.
以证明需要一个专门的系统
At this point, the answer is no, as I say, in the paper,
在这一点上 答案是否定的 正如我在论文中所说的
because is there does amazon or microsoft or google offer a vector database
因为亚马逊 微软或谷歌是否提供矢量
as a service?
数据库服务
No.
不
They could build one.
他们可以建造一个
They have unlimited money,
他们有无限的钱
but they don't see there being aa large market yet.
但他们还没有看到一个大市场
So I think it's still too early, but I think this could be the next thing.
所以我认为现在还为时尚早 但我认为这可能是下一件事
Right?
对的
And a there's a ton of these logos.
有很多这样的标志
It's hard to keep track.
很难跟踪
I clicked.
我点击了
All right.
好吧
What's going to happen in the future?
未来会发生什么
So I think right now we're in the golden era databases,
所以我认为现在我们正处于数据库的黄金时代
meaning like there's so many different choices, open source,
这意味着有这么多不同的选择
commercial cloud systems on pram.
开源 pram上的商业云系统
Sequel is considered the way to go forward right now.
续集被认为是现在前进的方向
Again, that'll change in 10 years,
再说一次 这将在10年内改变
but we'll be back again.
但我们会再次回来
An example would be all the new sql systems for 10 years ago,
一个例子是10年前的所有新SQL系统
except for retis.
除了RETIS
I've either died,
要么我已经死了
or they support sql and something that looks like the rational model.
要么他们支持SQL和一些看起来像Rational模型的东西
It's like1+1 equals 2 that basic arithmetic from thousands of years ago.
就像几千年前的基本算术1+1等于2
It stands the test of time because it's the right way to do this.
它经受住了时间的考验 因为这是正确的做法
That's what I sort of see the relational model.
这就是我在关系模型中看到的
Now sequel the best query language you could have
现在
for a relational database system.
Sequel是关系数据库系统的最佳查询语言
No.
不
There's obviously problems with it.
它显然有问题
But at this. there's so much buy and there's so much existing tooling
但在这个 有这么多的购买和有这么多的现有工具
and utilities that assume the sql database system.
和采用SQL数据库系统的实用程序
It would be very hard for anybody to change that.
任何人都很难改变这一点
Right?
对的
I there's so much fracturing in sequel itself,
Sequel本身有太多的分裂
how you come along say I have a new query language,
你怎么说我有一种新的查询语言
then everyone's going to start using it.
然后每个人都会开始使用它
Yeah, you could build your one system that does it,
是的 你可以建立一个这样的系统
but then nobody else is going to use it.
但没有其他人会使用它
So I don't know where sql is going to go with the future other than barring
所以我不知道SQL在未来会走向何方
ideas from other non sql systems.
除了禁止其他非SQL系统的想法
But I see the relational model being standing the test of time.
但我看到关系模式经受住了时间的考验
In my opinion.
在我看来
There's a reason why ted kahn won the touring world war.
泰德·卡恩赢得巡回世界大战是有原因的
Charles bachman won the turing wood for kodasal.
查尔斯·巴赫曼为柯达萨尔赢得了图灵木奖
First,
第一
the both days, it doesn't matter.
这两天 并不重要
All right.
好吧
So next class,
下节课
I got to go deal with some courts in seattle.
我要去西雅图的一些法院
Next week will be not in person.
下周将不会亲自
I'll post the monday lecture and wednesday lecture on youtube.
我将在YouTube上发布周一和周三的讲座
But we'll kick off starting talking about modern medical daily systems.
但我们将开球开始讨论现代医学日常系统
And we'll read about the papers about snowflake.
我们会读关于雪花的报纸
It's from the snowflake people.
它来自雪花人
There's some details about snowflake,
有一些关于雪花的细节
but I really want to understand the big idea of like running
但我真的很想了解在云中的共享
on a shared disk architecture in the cloud.
磁盘架构上运行的大想法
Make sure you submit your first reading of you
确保你提交了你的第一次阅读
before the class on2 o'clock wednesday,
在星期三下午2点上课之前
right?
对吗
I what did I say?
我我说什么了
No, there's no reading reviews.
不 没有阅读评论
No, there is a did I say tuesday?
不 我说的是星期二吗
No, I i'm just confused.
不 我只是有点困惑
Make sure you spend your first reading for you.
确保你的第一次阅读是为了你自己
Monday.
周一
Awesome, guys.
太棒了伙计们
Thank you.
谢谢
See you.
一会儿见
Ha, that's my favorite all that.
哈 那是我最喜欢的
What is it?
那是什么
It's the st cricket,
这是st cricket
idesi make a mess unless I can do it like ago ice cube with the g to the e
idesi弄得一团糟 除非我能像ago ice cube那样做
to the t here comes duke.
从g到e再到t杜克来了
I play the game.
我玩游戏
Where's no roof?
哪里没有屋顶
And poem is on the custody.
诗在监护权上
I'm a focus on drink fruit.
我专注于喝水果
Put the bus a cap on the eyes, bro, push.
把巴士的帽子放在眼睛上 兄弟 推
We gonna go with a blow to the eyes.
我们要在眼睛上打一拳
Indeed, that's me rolling with 5th one,
事实上 这是我与第五个
south park and south central g and thank us when I party.
南方公园和南部中心g一起滚动 并在我聚会时感谢我们
By the 12 pack case on the 46 pack,
通过46包上的12包箱子
48 gets the real price.
48得到了真实的价格
I drink fruit which are drinking about 12 hours,
我喝了大约12个小时的水果
they say bill makes you fat,
他们说比尔会让你变胖
but saying eyes is straight,
但他们说眼睛是直的
so it really don't matter.
所以这真的没关系